[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
科尔顿·奥格登：好的
COLTON OGDEN: All right.
欢迎来到GD50
Welcome to GD50.
这是第10课
This is lecture 10.
今天 我们将讨论“门户” “
Today we'll be talking about "Portal."
所以《传送门》是一款非常标志性的游戏 我想我们大多数人
So "Portal" is a very iconic game, I think most of us
可能以前见过
have probably seen it before.
要点是你有一把传送门枪 一把可以发射椭圆形传送门的枪
The gist is you have a portal gun, a gun that shoots these elliptical portals.
如果你仔细看 你可以有效地
If you look through one, you can effectively
看看另一个出来的是什么 这很酷 反之亦然
see what is coming out the other one, which is pretty cool, and vise versa.
然后 如果你走进传送门之间
And then, if you walk in between the portals,
你就会被传送到另一边
you'll actually be teleported to the other side.
因此 它们实现了很多非常有趣的效果
And so, they achieve a lot of really interesting effects
一些很酷的小把戏
with some pretty cool tricks and stuff.
实际上Valve自己也会来
And actually Valve themselves will be coming
做一个关于很多技术的演讲
to give a talk on a lot of the technology
他们在第二次使用
that they used on the second.
所以我们可以一窥他们的“传送门 “
So we can get a glimpse into their version of "Portal."
我的《传送门》版本更简单 但我们会
My version of "Portal" is a bit simpler, but we'll
看看很多类似的原理
look at a lot of the same sort of principles
看看我是如何完成很多相同的事情的
and see how I accomplished a lot of the same things.
这也是这学期的最后一节课
So this is also the last lecture of the semester,
我们已经调查了很多地方
and we've covered a lot of ground.
我这里有一些截图来展示一些游戏
I have a few screenshots here to show some of the games
我们已经讨论过了
that we've talked about.
第一个游戏是“乒乓” 我们已经走了很长的路
The very first game was "Pong," and we've come sort of a long way.
我们已经经历了非常简单的街机Atari类游戏
We have gone through very simple arcadey Atari-like games like this,
并且有效地创造了世界
and have gone and created worlds effectively.
现在我们在3D中 我们正在做各种各样的真棒的东西
And now we're in 3D, we're doing all kinds of awesome stuff.
但这是我们开始课程的地方
But this was where we started the course.
回顾过去看看我们走到了哪里是一件很有趣的事情
And it's kind of fun to look back and see where we've come.
在这里 我们讨论了计分和有效地绘制形状
So here, we talked about scoring and just effectively drawing shapes
然后我们切换到“Flappy Bird”或者“50 Bird”
onto the screen, then we transition to "Flappy Bird" or "50 Bird,"
我们有精灵和人物
and we had sprites and characters.
我们讨论了滚动和无限级过程生成
And we talked about scrolling and infinite level procedural generation
类型算法 这很有趣
type algorithms, and that was fun.
我们在《越狱》中更上一层楼
We took things a step higher than that with "Breakout"
我们有着相同的程序性想法
where we had the same sort of procedural ideas
在一个非常著名的街机游戏的背景下
in the context of a very famous arcade game.
我们谈到了粒子系统和一些街机风格
We talked about particle systems and some arcade style
物理和高分
physics and high scores.
然后我们开始玩益智游戏
Then we went into puzzle games.
我们谈到了第三场比赛 以及如何实际计算
We talked about Match Three" and how to actually calculate
是什么决定了我们是否找到了匹配的
what goes on to determine whether we have gotten a match
以及如何清理积木和如何补间事物
and how to clear blocks and how to tween things,
随着时间的推移进行操作 这是一种同步
do operations over time, sort of this A synchronicity.
然后我们进入了可能是我最喜欢的讲座
Then we went into probably what is my favorite lecture, which
是《超级马里奥兄弟》 我们聊了聊
was "Super Mario Brothers," and we talked
关于如何创建看起来完全不同的程序化世界
about how to create procedural worlds that all look very different
用一些非常简单的算法
with some very simple algorithms.
然后我们有了触发点和一些事件发生
And then we had triggers and events sort of happening.
然后《塞尔达传奇》问世了 我们有了这个无限地牢算法
Then "Legend of Zelda" came, and we had this infinite dungeon algorithm.
我们有敌人四处走动 我们
And we had enemies walking around that we
可以使用一把剑 所以感觉更像是一款实际的动作游戏 动作RPG
could use a sword on, so it felt more like an actual action game, action RPG.
然后在《愤怒的小鸟》中简要介绍了方框2D中的物理学
Then took a brief look at physics in the context of Box 2D with "Angry Birds,"
我还记得球坑的例子很可能是
and I still remember the ball pit example was probably
这是我最喜欢的部分
my favorite part of that.
然后可能是这学期最复杂的例子
And then probably the most complicated example of the semester
是《精灵宝可梦》 我们实际上有一个基于半满圈的
was "Pokemon," where we actually had a semi full turn based
并行系统 和随机相遇 就像一个小世界 在那里
parallel system, and random encounters, and like a little world where there's
实际上 我们的世界有两个主要阶段 那里有场
actually two main stages to our world where there was the field
还有战斗场面 这在RPG中是很常见的
and the battle scene, which is a very common thing to have in RPGs.
在《精灵宝可梦》之后 这是最复杂的代码库
Following "Pokemon," which was the most complicated codebase,
我们进入了Unity 这是我们第一次进军3D
we went into Unity, which was our first foray into 3D.
尽管我们只是在探索2.5D
And even though we were just exploring 2.5D,
我们仍然有机会了解Unity引擎是如何工作的 以及如何
we still got a chance to look at how does the Unity engine work and how do
我们把真实的3D模型搬上银幕？
we get actual 3D models onto the screen?
我们制作了一个非常简单的《飞鸟》风格的游戏
And we put together a very simple "Flappy Bird" esque game so
我们可以在某种程度上重复使用以前的想法
that we could sort of recycle prior ideas.
上周 我们看了《恐怖50》 这是一部恐怖的电影
Last week, we looked at "Dread 50," which was sort of a Dreadhall's horror
受启发的游戏 我们可以看到灯光
inspired game where we got to look at lighting
以及如何在场景之间进行实际转换 以及如何在Unity中使用一些基本的用户界面
and how to actually transition between scenes and use some basic UI in Unity.
今天 我们将讨论如何创建一个类似的游戏
And today, we'll be talking about how to create a game similar to this,
虽然简单多了
although much simpler.
今天基本上只是一个技术演示 而不是其他任何东西
Today is mostly just a tech demo more than anything else.
但这是实际游戏《门户》的截图
But this is a screenshot of the actual game "Portal."
正如你所看到的 他们做了很多非常酷的奇特的事情
And as you can see, they do a lot of really cool fancy things.
他们在斜坡上有一个入口 他们
They have a portal on sort of a slope, they
另一个入口从后面的前墙出来
have another portal coming out of the front wall over back there.
有不同的颜色 所以你可以区分左和右
There are different colors so you can differentiate between left and right,
橙色和蓝色
orange and blue.
他们在边上放着这样的东西
They have sort of this object here on the side,
我相信这是为了射出立方体 这就是这里
and I believe that's to shoot cubes out, which this here
是一个立方体 然后你可以用枪抓住它
is a cube which you can then grab with your gun
然后把它射进传送门 看着它进出传送门
and then shoot it through portals and see it come in and out of portals,
这真的很酷
which is pretty cool.
今天我们将讨论如何创建一个简单的版本 主要是
And we'll talk today about how to create a simple version of this, primarily
这只是我如何创建一个从另一个场景中看到的门户的方面
just the aspect of how do I create a portal that looks out of another scene
然后看到它实时更新吗？
and see it updating in real time?
我如何传送和往返于传送门之间
And how do I teleport and get back and forth between the portals
携带一件武器 然后发射一条射线 实际上会在那里放置一个传送门
and carry a weapon and then shoot a ray that will actually place a portal where
我想在游戏世界里吗？
I want to in the game world?
那么今天 我们要谈的一些话题
So today, some of the topics we'll talk about.
所以第一 拿着武器
So one, holding a weapon.
所以我们使用了第一人称控制器 这是
So we've used a first person controller, and this
这是一件非常容易和简单的事情
is a very easy and simple thing to do.
但它有助于解释什么是育儿
But it helps illustrate what parenting is.
所以我们会讨论这一点
And so we'll talk about that.
光线投射是从对象中实际射出光线
Ray casting is the actual shooting out of a ray from your object
向Z方向前进
to Z direction forward.
所以你有一个X和一个Y 这是你所处的角度
So you have an X and a Y, which are sort of the angle at which you're
四处走动
moving around.
但是你有Z 如果你使用前向向量
But then you have Z, which if you're using the forward vector
从你的角色来看 它将在z轴上向前
from your character, it's going to be forward in the z-axis
无论你在哪里有效地寻找
wherever you're looking effectively.
从这个意义上说 这让我们可以投射一条射线 也就是投篮
And so that allows us to cast a ray, in that sense, which just means shoot
一条直线 从那一点开始的一条看不见的直线
a straight line, an invisible straight line from that point,
在该点与物体相交的任何地方
and wherever that point intersects with an object,
我们可以得到一些相关的信息 然后做
we can get some information about that and then do
无论我们需要做什么工作
whatever work we need to do.
在这种情况下 取一个门户预制件 基本上只需将其固定在墙上即可
In this case, take a portal prefab and just affix it to the wall, basically.
将其从默认位置旋转 然后
Rotate it from its default position, and then just
把它平放在墙上
put it flat up against the wall.
纹理遮罩是我们实现这种门户效果的方式 对吗？
Texture masking is how we're going to achieve this portal effect, right?
因为当我们在Unity中创建所谓的渲染纹理时 这里是
Because when we create what's called a render texture in Unity, which here's
第三个项目符号 渲染纹理的意思是纹理
the third bullet, a render texture just means a texture
我们用摄像机渲染到的图像
that we're rendering to with a camera.
因此 与其让纹理成为游戏中的资产 不如在您的层次结构中
So rather than have a texture be an asset in your game, in your hierarchy
用你在Photoshop中制作的东西
with something that you made in Photoshop,
您实际上可以在运行时动态创建它
you can actually dynamically create it at runtime
与摄像机所看到的相吻合
with what the camera is seeing.
Unity很容易就会免费给你这个
And Unity gives this to you for free very easily
使用所谓的渲染纹理 这只是另一种资源类型
with what's called a render texture, which is just another asset type.
然后纹理遮罩实际上也是同样的事情
And then texture masking is effectively the same thing
作为模板 我们可以选择要删除的对象的某些像素
as stenciling where we can choose certain pixels of an object to delete.
在本例中 我们创建了一个中间是白色 然后是黑色的纹理
In this case, we create a texture that's white in the center and then black
围绕着边缘呈椭圆形
around the edges in an elliptical shape.
这让我们可以用一个简单的着色器来告诉它
And what that allows us to do is tell it with a simple shader,
在实际渲染渲染纹理时不要渲染这些像素
don't render these pixels when you actually render the render texture,
只需渲染中间的那些
just render the ones in the middle.
因此 这就是我们如何实现椭圆 仅仅通过有效地
And so, that's how we achieve an ellipse, just by effectively
丢弃外圈中的像素
discarding the pixels in the outer rim.
贴花是3D游戏中的一个想法 在3D游戏中 贴花只是一种
Decals is an idea in 3D games where a decal is just something
将纹理或某个对象粘贴到表面上
that you affix a texture or some object that you affixed to a surface.
在本例中 我们将使用贴花作为我们的门户
In this case, we'll be using decals to act as our portal.
所以我们的门户实际上只会是贴花
So our portals are actually just going to be decals.
它们只是附着了渲染纹理的网格
They're just meshes with a render texture affixed to them.
然后我们所要做的就是每当我们拍摄它的时候就把它们拍到墙上
And then all we need to do is just slap them onto a wall whenever we shoot it,
我们得到了一条与墙相交的光线
and we get a ray that intersects with the wall.
这将会产生实际的效果
And that will have the effect of actually making
它看起来像是我们在墙上建了一个入口 而实际上 我们
it look like we're putting a portal on a wall, when in reality, we're
只是拿一个网眼 我们就像是把它拍到墙上一样
just taking a mesh and we're kind of just like slapping it onto a wall.
你可能在其他游戏中见过的其他一些贴花的例子
Some other examples of decals that you've probably seen in other games
例如 使用相同原理的弹孔
are, for example, bullet holes, which use the same principle.
远程传送非常简单 尽管FPS控制器
Teleporting is very easy, although the FPS controller sort
会让事情变得有点复杂
of complicates things a little bit.
因此 我们将讨论如何以及如何解决传送问题
So we'll talk about how and about sort of solving the problem of teleporting
在某种程度上 这是有意义的
in a way that makes sense.
它通常就像设置某个对象的变换位置一样简单
It's usually just as simple as setting something's transforms position
到另一个变换位置 设置旋转
to another transforms position, setting the rotation
设置为变换旋转
to the transforms rotation.
但是FPS控制器将其旋转数据变现
But the FPS controller cashes its rotation data,
所以为了干净利落地传送 你可以说
so in order to that teleport cleanly you sort of
必须覆盖某些默认行为
have to override some default behavior.
最后 我们来看看一些新工具
And lastly, we'll take a look at some new tools
Unity在2018年0.1 Pro Builder和Pro中推出了
that Unity has introduced with 2018 0.1 Pro Builder and Pro
栅格 允许您在场景中实际建模几何体
Grids, which allow you to actually model geometry in the scene.
这就是这份作业要关注的重点
And this is what the assignment is going to be focused on.
因为展望未来 我预见它将成为现代统一的重要组成部分
Because going forward, I foresee it being a major part of modern unity
开发和/或原型制作
development and or prototyping.
无需第三方程序即可在Unity中为场景建模的能力
The ability to model your scene in Unity without needing a third party program
大大优化了实际的创建过程
heavily optimizes the actual creation process
它可以让你轻松地完成所谓的
and allows you to do easy, what's called,
“灰色拳击” 意思是在你的游戏引擎中创建一个关卡 然后制作原型
"gray boxing," meaning create a level in your game engine and then prototype it,
测试它 确保它真的可以马上玩游戏
test it, make sure that it's actually game playable right off the bat.
这叫做“灰色拳击”
That's called "gray boxing."
但首先 让我们来做一个演示
But first, let's get a demo.
那么 有没有人想来这里玩我的“门户”的实现？
So does anybody want to come up here and play my implementation of "Portal?"
所以詹姆斯是内陆国
So James is landlocked.
好了 詹姆斯 你不是内陆的
All right James, you're not landlocked.
我们走吧
Let's go.
好的 现在我要开始设置了
All right, so I'm going to go ahead and set that up.
所以免责声明 实际上这里面有一个漏洞
And so disclaimer, there's actually a bug in this
所以我很好奇你能不能发现这个bug
as well, so I'm curious to see if you can spot what the bug is.
准备好了就按播放键
Go ahead and hit play as soon as you're ready.
然后右边的鼠标将是你的角度你的门户
And then the mouse on the right will be your angle your portal.
所以我们在这里看到我有一个创建了一把传送门枪的角色
So we see here I have a character with a portal gun created.
詹姆斯 如果你用鼠标左键射击一面墙 就会产生一个传送门.
So James, if you shoot a wall with the left mouse, that will create a portal.
然后如果用鼠标右键
And then if use the right mouse--
这是另一个bug
so that's one other bug.
所以让我们重新启动程序
So let's go ahead and restart the program, actually.
这是一个bug
So that's one bug.
因此 如果我们避免踏入那里的入口
And so, if we avoid stepping into a portal that's there--
这个问题可以通过几种方式来解决
and this this could be fixed in a couple of ways.
所以现在你有两个门户网站基本上创建
So now you have two portals basically created.
你看到这两个入口的问题了吗
Do you see what's wrong with the portal as it is here, both of these portals
是吗
actually?
哦 实际上 不 对不起 这些入口实际上是完全正确的
Oh actually, no, I'm sorry, these portals are actually completely right.
但要穿过它们
But walk through them.
我会告诉你
And I will show you--
好的 你可以看到它工作得很好 对吧？
OK, so you can see it works pretty well, right?
你不仅可以看到你的角色完全渲染或移动
You can not only see your character rendering completely or moving
在实时的时候 其他的纹理 但你可以通过他们跳
in real time when the other texture, but you can jump through them
或者穿过它们
or walk through them.
如果你愿意 你可以用空格键跳跃
You can jump with spacebar if you want, and that'll
把你传送到另一端
teleport you throughout the other end so you
从另一个门户的角度来看
see from the perspective of the other portal.
但如果我们试着射击另一面墙
But if we try shooting one of the other walls
比如说 像这些白墙
for instance, like one of these white walls,
你会发现这面墙有些奇怪
you can see something weird happens with this particular wall.
你觉得那个传送门有什么奇怪的吗？
Anything strike you as odd about that portal?
有人知道吗？
Anybody?
它是颠倒的
It's upside down.
所以如果你穿过它 它工作得很好
And so if you walk through it though, it works perfectly fine.
现在它被颠倒的原因是 我花了大概10 15个小时
Now the reason that it's upside down, I spent probably like 10, 15 hours
试图弄清楚为什么它处于一种状态
trying to figure out why this is, it's in a state
所谓的“平衡环锁定”“
of what's called "gimbal lock."
这个预制件在三维空间里有三个旋转轴
So this prefab right here, there's three axis of rotation in 3D space.
如果你以某种奇怪的方式旋转
And if you perform a rotation in some odd way,
有一种东西叫做加油器角度
there are these things called oiler angles,
也就是你绕x y z轴旋转的角度
which are your angles of rotation about the x,y and z-axis.
你可以把它们想象成某种
And you can sort of think of them as sort
能够相互依赖地旋转
of being able to rotate interdependently.
但在某种情况下 你可以--
But there is a situation in which you can--
出于某种原因 单位旋转的内部表示
for some reason, Unity's internal representation of a rotation
可以通过操纵这些角度来搞砸
can get messed up by manipulating these angles.
所以 你实际上可以把两个轴锁在一起
And so, you can actually lock two axes together such
旋转--例如 在这个例子中 它是Z和Y
that rotating-- like for example, in this case, it's Z and Y,
它们都相互旋转
they both rotate each other.
因此 在这种情况下 你不能让门户旋转
And so you're unable to get, in this particular case, the portal to rotate
关于让它看起来像它的右侧向上的轴
about the axis that lets it look like its right side up based
在墙的表面法线上
on the wall's surface normal.
所以 如果我再多一个星期 我可能已经调试过了
And so, had I maybe another week, I probably could have debugged it,
但我不得不把它留在里面
but I had to leave it in.
不幸的是 我没时间了
Unfortunately, I ran out of time.
但有趣的是 如果你真的拍摄同一面墙--
But the interesting thing is if you do shoot that same wall--
所以试着拍那面墙 另一面墙--
so try and shoot that wall, the other wall with--
就像把两个门都放在马车墙上 所以是右边的墙
like put both portal on the buggy wall, so the right wall.
顺便说一句 出于某种原因 只是那堵墙
It's only that wall, by the way, for some reason.
所以请注意 现在它的右边朝上了
So notice that now its right side up.
所以如果你在同一面墙上拍摄两个入口 那堵墙
So if you shoot both portals on the same wall, that buggie wall,
它们确实是正面朝上的
they do get right side up.
而我无论如何也不能确切地确定原因
And I for the life of me couldn't ascertain exactly as to why.
我知道这是万向节锁
I know it's gimbal lock.
不幸的是 我无法及时对其进行调试
Unfortunately, I was unable to debug it quite in time.
但每隔一面墙 包括天花板和地板
But every other wall, including the ceiling and the floor,
如果你向他们发射传送门就行了
will work if you shoot a portal up on them.
所以你可以在上面创建一个 然后你就可以跳过它
So you can create one up there, and then you can jump through it.
看看它是怎么往下看的 然后它就会把你放在顶端
See how it's looking down, and then it'll put you at the top.
总而言之 除去万向节锁住传送门的奇怪的单一墙壁
And altogether, minus the weird single wall that gimbal locks the portal,
我们有一个非常实用的实现
we have a pretty functional implementation
一款非常基本的门户游戏 对吧？
of a very basic portal game, right?
我们有这样一个模式 就是在镜头前为人父母
We have this model here is parenting to the camera.
所以它总是会看向与相机完全相同的方向
So it's always going to look in the exact same direction as the camera.
我们从枪尖射出一束光线 然后
We shoot a ray from the tip of the gun, and then
每当光线与平面相交 在这种情况下 这些墙中的任何一面
whenever that ray intersects with a plane, in this case any of these walls,
我们得到了关于交叉口的信息
we get the information about the intersection
我们翻转传送门贴花 这样它就
and we flip the portal decal so that it's
与墙旋转的角度相同
the same angle as the wall rotation.
然后 当我们实际上与其中一个入口相撞时会发生什么
And then what happens when we actually collide with one of the portals just
在代码中 如果我们考虑如何实现
in code if we were to think about how to implement
在这里发生的行为？
the behavior that goes on here?
它是在运送球员
It's transporting the player.
它有效地设置了球员转换后的位置
And it's doing effectively setting the player's transformed position
设置到与门户相同的变换位置
to the same transform position as the portal.
现在 如果我们在轮换时做同样的事情
Now, if we do the same thing on the rotation,
FPS控制器的旋转有点歪斜
the FPS controller's rotation gets a bit skewed
如果您弄乱了它的X和Z旋转 默认控制器
if you mess with it's X and Z rotation, the default controller.
所以我们现在所做的就是保持这些值 X和Y旋转
So all we do for now is we just keep those values, the X and Y rotation,
但我们只是改变了Y旋转
but we just change the Y rotation.
Y旋转是它在空间中的位置 就像这样
Y rotation is its position in space like this effectively.
所以当我们从墙里跳出来的时候
So that allows us to get when we jump out of the wall,
我们注意到他是扁平的 但如果我们跳过任何一面墙
we notice that he's flat from it, but if we jump through any of the wall
传送门--如果你在这里的墙上创建传送门
portals-- so if you create a portal on the wall here,
然后跳过它 你会注意到你有点成角度
and then jump through it, you'll notice that you're sort of angled
在右边--
at the right--
它倾斜的原因是因为这个是颠倒的
and the reason that it's skewed is because this one is upside down.
因此 它翻转了渲染纹理的相机
And so it's flipping the camera that's rendering the texture
它看起来有点奇怪
and it's looking a little bit weird.
但当你跳过时 它基本上保持了你的X和Z
But when you jump through, it basically keeps your X and Z,
但旋转你的Y位置 这样你就出来了
but rotates your Y position so that you come out
看起来就像是直接通过了入口 而不是默认的
looking as if you went straight through the portal, rather than by default,
它让你回头看你出来的门户 这有点奇怪
it has you look back at the portal that you came out of, which is a bit weird.
或者无论你朝哪个方向穿过它
Or whatever direction you were walking through it
当你穿过传送门的时候
when you went through the portal.
观众：你怎么弄到镜子[INAUDIBLE] 这样你就能看到你自己了？
AUDIENCE: How are you getting the mirror [INAUDIBLE] so you can see yourself?
科尔顿·奥格登：这是默认设置 因为它是渲染纹理
COLTON OGDEN: That's just default because it's a render texture.
所以每个入口后面实际上都有一个摄像头
So there's a camera actually behind each of these portals.
因此 预制是一个带有渲染纹理的网格
So the prefab is a mesh with a render texture.
然后在它的后面 有一个摄像头
And then behind it, there's a camera.
因此 摄像机正在实时呈现入口前的情况
And so, the camera is rendering in real time what's in front of the portal,
基本上 是从它的后面
basically, from behind it.
所以它从这两个门户看到了你的模型
And so it's seeing your model from both of these portals,
两个摄像头都能看到你的模特 所以它就出现了
both cameras are seeing your model, and so it shows up
在另一个门户上的渲染纹理中
in the render texture on the other portal.
因此 这实际上就像是在看两个摄像机 而不是一个门户
So it's effectively like looking at two video cameras instead of a portal.
这是一种诡计
It's sort of a trick.
这是“门户”的一个非常粗糙的实现
And this is a very crude implementation of "Portal,"
实际的游戏使用了一个复杂得多的算法--
the actual game uses a much more sophisticated algorithm for--
它还可以用摄像头跟踪你的位置
and it also tracks your position with the camera
所以根据你的旋转角度 你会
so that based on your angle of rotation, you'll
实际上在那里的纹理上看到了一些不同的东西
actually see something different on the texture there.
但把这样的东西放在一起要复杂得多
But it's a lot more complicated to put something like that together.
我有一些资源 我已经在作业的讲课中包含了
I have some resources that I've included in the lecture in the assignment that
将会向你展示如何做到这一点
will show you actually how to do that.
但这比我制作这个演示所需的时间要多得多
But it would take many, many more hours than I had to put this demo together.
观众：是的 现在只是修好了
AUDIENCE: Yeah, right now it's just fixed.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 已经修好了
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah it's fixed.
如果你真的从侧面看
If you actually look at it from the side,
你会注意到它只是一个平坦的纹理
you'll notice that it's just a flat texture.
没有远见
There's no perspective.
归根结底 它的视角
Ultimately, its perspective.
有一个很棒的视频 我要去看
And there's an awesome video that I'm going
在稍后的幻灯片中 一位名叫Braxis的YouTuber展示了他实际上
to show later in the slides by a YouTuber named Braxis where he actually
实现一个透视正确的着色器 允许您查看
implements a perspective correct shader that allows you to see,
并用摄像机跟踪玩家
and with camera tracking of the player.
就像两个摄像头都会跟踪玩家的位置一样
Like both cameras will track the position of the player,
以及渲染纹理
as well as render a texture.
其结果是因为摄像机正在改变它们的位置
And the result of that is because the cameras are changing their position,
这有点像改变场景的角度
it's sort of like changing the angle at which the scene is
被渲染到门户网格上
being rendered onto the portal mesh.
但它的绘制方式也有一点不同
But also the way that it's being drawn is a little bit different,
因此 他有一个非常酷的着色器来实现这一点
and so he has a really cool shader that does that.
然后Vavle 当他们出现的时候 他们会
And then Vavle, when they present, they'll
实际上展示了他们是如何做的 这甚至更复杂
actually show how they went about doing it, which is even more complex,
但它看起来真的很好 在技术上更有趣
but it looks really good and is a lot more technically interesting.
但是 是的 这是我的基本实现
But yeah, that's my sort bare bones implementation
是什么让“门户”发挥作用
of what makes "Portal" work.
穿过这些入口是一件很有趣的事
And it's somewhat fun to walk through these portals
就像是在玩弄它
and just sort of play around with it.
现在 如果你走进一个蓝色的门户 它不起作用的原因是
Now the reason that if you just walk into a blue portal it doesn't work
是因为门户实际上存储在屏幕之外 直到您使用它们
is because the portals are actually stored off screen until you use them.
我将在这里打开场景
I'll open up the scene here.
哦 顺便说一句 谢谢詹姆斯来看演示
Oh, by the way, thanks James for coming up to demo.
我很感激
I appreciate it.
所以入口在这里 对吗？
So the portals are over here, right?
他们两个都在这里
Both of them are right here.
因此 当你只射杀其中一人时
And so what that does is when you only shoot one of them,
另一个还在这里 所以当你走过它的时候
the other one is still out here, so when you walk through it
你最终只是在水平之外进行心灵传送
you end up just teleporting outside the level.
为了不让这种情况发生 你真正需要做的是
And in order to not have that happen, what you really need to do
两个人身上都有一面旗子 上面写着
is have a flag on both of them that just says
除非你中过一枪 否则不要传送 对吗？
don't teleport unless you've been shot once, right?
这将防止这种行为的发生
And that will prevent that sort of behavior from happening.
简单的解决办法 但一个有趣的看一看
Simple fix, but an entertaining one to take a look at.
这就是我对“门户”的粗略实现
And that is my crude implementation of "Portal."
它远没有真正的游戏那么完美
It's far from being anywhere near as polished as the actual game.
还有一堵小小的奇怪的墙 那个万向节
And there is the slight weird wall that gimbal
锁住了传送门 我想弄清楚这到底是为什么
locks the portal, which I would like to figure out why exactly that is.
但其他的东西都在这里
But everything else is sort of in here.
现在 它不包括像通过它投篮这样的东西
Now, it doesn't include something like shooting blocks through it,
但同样的原则也适用于
but the same sort of principles would apply
因为我们在门户上所做的一切实际上就是在说--
because all we're effectively doing on the portal is saying--
它基本上是一个引爆器 对吗？
it's basically a trigger, right?
上面有个盒子对撞机 上面写着如果我撞到什么东西
It's got a box collider on it, and it says if I collide with something,
在这种情况下 玩家 我想传送对撞机
and in this case the player, I want to teleport that collider
到另一个门户 这意味着这些门户有点像
to the other portal, which means that the portals sort of have
相互链接 对吗？
to link to each other, right?
一个门户必须引用另一个门户
One portal has to have a reference to the other portal
这样它就可以说 “传送到链接的门户 ”
so that it can say, "Teleport to the linked portal."
反之亦然 链接门户应该有一个参考
And vise versa, the link portal should have a reference
到其他门户网站 上面写着 “远程传送
to the other portals that can say, "Teleport
如果你撞到这个 就会后退 “
back if you collide with this."
所以 如果我们有另一个物体--比如说 我们向传送门发射一个立方体
And so, if we have another object-- like say, we shoot a cube into the portal,
它也会被传送到另一个入口 对吗？
it would also get teleported to the other portal, right?
另一个需要考虑的问题是 如果它是刚体
And the other consideration for that is like if its a rigid body
例如 它应用了物理学
and it has physics applied to it, for example,
假设它在X上的速度是10 它传送
let's say its going like 10 on the X and it teleports
到一个垂直于它的入口 它仍然是10到X
to a portal that's perpendicular to it and it's still going 10 to the X,
一旦它从传送门发射出去
then as soon as it shoots out the portal,
它会一直向左转 这不是我们想要的行为
it's going to go straight left, which isn't the behavior we want.
我们希望它能向前发展
We want it to go forward.
因此 线速度需要校准
So linear velocity needs to be calibrated
朝着不同的方向前进
to go in a different direction.
没有足够的时间来制作一个完整的演示
Didn't have enough time to put a full demo of that together,
但如果你很好奇 简而言之 那就是
but if you were curious, in a nutshell, that's
有点像您需要做的事情 以实现
sort of like what you would need to do in order to implement
关于《门户》的一些基本物理知识
some basic physics with "Portal."
所以拿着武器
So holding a weapon.
根据这张截图 有谁能告诉我
Based on this screen shot, can anybody tell me
他们认为我从一个普通的FBS控制员
how they think I went from just a plain FBS controller,
一名手持枪支的联邦调查局控制员
to an FBS controller holding a gun.
观众：你能像一把枪一样--
AUDIENCE: Can you stick a gun, like one--
他们把它叫做有色像素吗--相机前面的一个单元？
do they call it colored pixels-- one unit in front of the camera?
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
3D空间中的像素并不一定是一个概念
There's not really a notion necessarily of pixels in 3D space
因为这取决于你的分辨率
because that changes depending on your resolution.
但是 是的 联合部队--
But yes, Unity units--
它实际上相当于一米 你可以改变
it's effectively equivalent to a meter, and you can change
它在Unity设置中表示的内容
what it represents in Unity settings.
不过 是的
But yeah.
我的意思是 这不一定是一个单位
I mean, it doesn't necessarily have to be one unit.
它可以是一个任意的数量
It can be an arbitrary amount.
而我真正要做的就是带着这个模特来到这里
And what it really was me going into here with this model.
顺便说一句 我在评估商店免费买到了这个模型
By the way, I got this model on the Assess Store for free.
因此 如果你正在寻找 评估商店是一个很棒的地方
So the Assess Store is an awesome place if you're looking
来快速制作你的游戏原型
to just quickly prototype your game.
他们没有任何明显的类似传送门的枪 看起来真的很好
They didn't have any obvious portal gun lookalikes that looked really good.
所以我就说 “哦 这些枪的颜色都一样
So I was like, "Oh, this guns got like the same kind of color.
我就选这个吧
I'll just choose this.
就像科幻小说里的枪“
It's like a sci-fi kind of gun."
但你也看到了这里有等级制度
But as you can see, there's a hierarchy here.
现在 我们怎么把枪固定在摄像头所看到的地方
Now, how are we keeping the gun affixed to where the camera is looking,
我们知道吗？
do we know?
观众：你做的事情和你做的第一人称射击游戏一样
AUDIENCE: You do the same thing as you do with the first person shooter
密码是让摄像机跟着枪走或者反过来
code is you have the camera follow the gun or vice versa.
科尔顿·奥格登：你让摄像机跟着枪
COLTON OGDEN: You have the camera follow the gun.
你对我们的进展有什么猜测吗？
Do you have any guesses to how we're doing?
这其实是一件非常非常简单的事情
It's actually a really, really simple thing.
观众：我知道我在做 但是[听不见]
AUDIENCE: I know i'm doing it, but [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：所以我们所做的一切--
COLTON OGDEN: So all we're doing--
噢 史蒂文
Oh, Steven.
观众：我想问的是 你把摄像机设置成
AUDIENCE: I was going to say do you set the cameras to transform
如[不可闻]
as [INAUDIBLE].
枪的变形有偏移量吗 比如同一个方向
Do the guns transform with an offset, like in the same direction
但有位置偏移吗
but with a position offset?
是的
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
算是吧
Kind of.
除了枪变换到相机变换 但只是有一个偏移
Except the guns transform to the cameras transform, but just with an offset.
这就是我们正在做的
And that is effectively what we're doing.
为了实现这一目标
And in order to accomplish that, it's really
就像让它成为那个东西的孩子一样简单
as simple as just making it a child of that thing.
这是第一人称角色控制器
So this is the first person character controller.
上面有个摄像头
It's got a camera attached to it.
任何你把别的东西变成孩子的东西
Anything that you make a child of something else,
它也会有同样的变化
it's going to have the same transform changes applied to it,
包括轮换
including rotation.
所以通过把枪做成第一人称角色的孩子
So by making the gun just a child of the first person character, which
就是摄像机的位置
is where the camera is here--
第一人称角色 顺便说一下
first person character, by the way, is just
FPS控制器的子组件 我将其重命名为
a subcomponent of the FPS controller, which I renamed
传送门枪FPS控制器
to portal gun FPS controller here.
传送门枪 任何时候这个第一人称角色
The portal gun, anytime this first person character
也就是摄像机 所以只要摄像机旋转
is rotated, which is the camera, so anytime the camera is rotated,
它会将旋转作用到传送门枪上 这个枪网
it applies that rotation to the portal gun here, this gun mesh.
所以 这给了你效果
And so, that gives you the effect.
所以你要做的就是在3D空间里像这样开始
So what you do is you start it off in 3D space like this.
你在看你的游戏场景 你有你的角色
You're looking at your game scene, and you have your character.
然后你移动你的枪支物体
And then you move your gun object around.
在这种情况下 让我们从两个布局到三个布局
In this case, let's go to layouts two by three.
所以你可以实时看到它
So you can see it in real time.
这是游戏视图 这是在Startup上的样子
This is the game view, this is what it's going to look like on Startup.
我将在这里转到我的编辑视图
I'm going to go over to my editor view here.
我只需要在这里拿到实际的枪支部件
And I'm just going to grab the actual gun component here,
我应该说的是枪支物体
the gun object I should say.
去把它放好 我就可以移动它了 对吗？
Go and position it, and I can just move it, right?
这就是你如何改变你的枪相对于相机的位置
And so this is how you can change where your gun is relative to the camera.
这会影响它的感觉 对吗？
And this is going to affect sort of how it feels, right?
就像我可以把它放在这里 它有点低 我可以把它放在这里
Like I could put it here and it's kind of a little lower, I could put it here,
这显然感觉有点奇怪 因为它没有手在上面
it feels a little weird obviously because it doesn't have a hand on it.
因此 它看起来几乎就像一款VR游戏
So it almost looks like a VR game.
这就是VR游戏所做的 它们会占据你的手的位置
And that's kind of what VR games do is they take your hand positions
然后枪的变形基本上锁定在你手的位置
and then the gun transform is locked to basically where your hand
控制器是
controllers are.
在这种情况下 我所做的只是定位它
In this case, all I did was I just positioned it.
我说：“我喜欢它现在的样子 所以我就这么做 ”
I said, "I like how it looks right here, so I'm just going to do that."
一旦我让它成为第一人称角色的孩子
And as soon as I make it a child of the first person character, which
就是相机 它只会把所有的旋转都应用到它身上
is the camera, it's just going to get all the rotations applied to it.
所以 每当我们像我在这里所做的那样 对着摄像机做任何旋转
So anytime we make any rotations to the camera, which I'm doing here,
它与相机保持精确对准
it stays exactly aligned with the camera.
这适用于您在Unity中执行的任何操作
This applies to any operation that you do in Unity
进行任何类型的变换时 位置比例都会发生变化
when you make any sort of transform position scale changes.
它们都是沿着链条传播的
They all get propagated down the chain.
属于以下对象的子级的所有对象
All the objects that are children of an object that
应用于它们的Get Transform操作将具有相同的Transform操作
get transform operations applied to them will have the same transform operations
适用于他们
applied to them.
有点像这种递归的效果
Sort of like this recursive kind of effect.
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：所以如果你导入第一人称控制器
AUDIENCE: So if you import the first person controller,
[听不见]有跳跃和左右移动
[INAUDIBLE] has jump and moves left and right.
然后你只需移动你的资产 你的枪 放在控制器下面
And then you just move your asset, your gun, to be underneath that controller,
它就会跟着来吗？
it would just follow?
科尔顿·奥格登：正确
COLTON OGDEN: Correct.
所以如果你只是导入香草FPS控制器 然后只是使枪
So if you just import the vanilla FPS controller, and then just make the gun.
具体来说 枪需要是这个的孩子 第一人称
Specifically, the gun needs to be a child of this, the first person
因为它有摄像头
character bit because that has the camera.
回想一下 相机是驱动我们旋转的 对吗？
And recall, the camera is what's driving our rotation, right?
因为我们用鼠标移动摄像机的旋转
Because we're moving the camera's rotation with our mouse.
这将最终决定
That is ultimately going to determine how
该变换被应用于枪
the transform gets applied to the gun.
但我知道
But yes.
所以每当我们在Unity中做任何事情时--你会做很多事情
And so whenever we're doing anything in Unity-- and you'll do a lot of things
一个物体的移动、缩放或旋转应该应用于另一个物体
where one things movement or scale or rotation should apply to another thing,
记住这通常就像
just remember that's usually just as easy as making
它是别的东西的孩子
it a child of something else.
关于我们是如何实施武器的还有其他问题吗？
So any other questions as to how we've gone about implementing the weapon?
好吧
All right.
所以光线投射
So ray casting.
所以光线投射是Unity免费提供的一个很好的功能
So ray casting is a nice feature that Unity gives you for free.
它是Unity中物理命名空间的一部分
It's part of the physics sort of name space in Unity.
脚本API的一部分
Part of the scripting API.
它能让你有效地
And what it allows you to do is effectively
从你正在进行的任何变换中看
look at from whatever transform you're operating at,
或者你把它作为源的任何变换
or whatever transform you give it as the source,
所以无论你给它一个点作为源 你都可以告诉它一个方向
so whatever point you give it as the source, you can tell a direction,
给它一个矢量作为方向
give it a vector as a direction.
在这种情况下 我们要做的就是transform. forward
In this case, what we're doing is we're saying transform.forward.
transform.forward的意思是
And transform.forward just means basically
无论我们看X和Y 然后直接在Z方向
wherever we're looking X and Y, and then straight in the Z direction.
所以如果你在摄像机前做
So if you're doing it on a camera, it's always
就跟你现在看到的一样
going to be exactly what you're looking at.
它总是向前的
It's always going to be exactly forward on the--
transform.相机的前向总是像屏幕的中心
transform.foward on a camera is always going to be like center of the screen
无论你在哪里看
wherever you're looking at.
所以如果我们从我们的性格出发--
And so if we cast a ray from the point of our character--
或者说我们是用枪来完成的
or actually we're doing it from the point of our gun,
到transform.forward--就像一条从玩家到transform的线
to the transform.forward-- like a line going from our player to transform
它的特征的前向矢量 我们的相机的前向矢量
the forward vector of its character, the forward vector of our camera,
它将产生这样的效果--
it's going to have the effect of--
我们可以射击一些东西 对吗？
we can shoot something, right?
我们可以创建光线投射 然后在光线相交的任何地方附加一些东西
We can create a ray cast and then affix something wherever that ray intersects.
它将位于我们相机视野的正中央
And it'll be at the exact center of our camera view.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
所以你从你的z轴拍一条线 这是你的正向向量
So you shoot a line from your z-axis, which is your forward vector.
然后根据你旋转相机的方式
And then based on how you've rotated the camera,
X和Y是其中的X和Y部分 Z总是向前的
X and Y are the X and Y part of that, and Z is always forward,
这将让你直接在你面前投射物体或投射光线
that'll let you shoot things or cast rays directly in front of you.
您可以在任何对象之间、从任何源点投射光线
And you can cast rays between any object and from any source point
任何你想要的方向
with any sort of direction you want.
但它在上下文中特别相关
But it's particularly pertinent in the context
我们是如何用我们的枪射击它的
of how we've shot it from our gun.
所以这是一张屏幕截图 它看起来是什么样子
And so here is a screenshot actually of what that looks like.
因此 统一的好处实际上是
And so the nice thing about Unity actually
它是否有一个名为或调试.dragray的函数
is it has a function called or debug.drawray,
我会在这里展示给你们看
which I'll show you here.
我在一个名为调试射线的组件中实现了它
I implemented it in a component called debug ray,
这样您就可以实际看到光线在场景中的投射位置
so that you can actually see where a ray is being cast in your scene
并消除任何模棱两可的地方
and eliminate any ambiguity there.
因此您可以看到绘制光线、转换位置 然后
So you can see draw ray, transform.position, and then
我们只说变形 从方向变形
we just say transform.transfromdirection,
向量3前进 然后乘以1,000表示从该点开始的1,000个单位
vector3.forward, and then times 1,000 just means 1,000 units from that point.
然后是红色
And then color.red.
所以这将会做的是--只有在编辑视图中
And so what that will do is-- only in the editor view,
所以这并不适用于实际的游戏
so this doesn't apply in the actual game.
这只是一个调试调用 DEBUG.Drawray
This is just a debug call, debug.drawray.
所以它将在这里的场景中渲染 只是在这里没有完成
And so it'll render in this scene up here, just not done here.
因此 如果我们点击Play 我实际上拥有所有的门户
So if we hit play, I actually have all the portals
从他们的正向变换和我的枪渲染调试光线
rendering a debug ray from their forward transform and from my gun.
所以你可以在那里看到 我只是在调试 Dragray
So you can see it there, I'm just doing a debug.drawray
只需转换.foward 并使用我的转换位置作为源点
with just transform.foward and using my transform.position as the source point.
注意Z方向的箭头
And notice that Z arrow.
它总是沿着同一个方向前进 对吗？
It's always following the same direction, right?
X和Y在某种程度上改变了底板
X and Y are sort of changing the backplanes
排序就像旋转一样 但是Z总是向前的 对吗？
sort are like how that's rotated, but Z is always forward, right?
这就是我们的枪发出的光线
And so that's the ray coming from our gun.
如果我们在那里和那里发射传送门 我也会把它们设置成--
And if we shoot a portal there and there, I have those also set to--
让我暂停一下 这样我可以稍微旋转一下视图
let me pause so I can rotate the view a little bit.
我也准备好了从他们的前锋位置引出一条光线
I have those also set to draw a ray from their forward position.
因此 这些也从他们的转变中吸取了一丝光芒 向前看
So those are also drawing a ray from what's their transform.foward,
它们的方向向量
their directional vector.
但没错 是光线选角
But yeah, ray casting.
以这种方式进行一些非常简单的碰撞测试是相当容易的
It's pretty easy just to get some pretty simple collision tests this way
用枪 用很多不同的东西
with guns, with a lot of different things.
但主要是 你会看到它被用来计算一些东西
But primarily, you'll see this used for like calculating whether something
是在阻挡其他东西
is blocking something else.
比如如果一辆车在移动 也许它检测到了另一辆车 就像《Grand》中的
Like if a car is moving and maybe it detects another car, like in "Grand
偷窃汽车“ 例如
Theft Auto," for example.
你的车开到了路中央什么的
And your car is driving down the center of the road or something
它想知道它前面两个单元是否有一辆车
and it wants to know whether there's a car two units in front of it
或者别的什么
or something.
你只需投射一条光线 看看是否有任何几何体
You just cast a ray and see if there's any geometry
从它的前向向量开始 对吗？
there from its forward vector, right?
变换位置、汽车位置 然后
Transform.position, car.position, and then
获取其正向向量 该向量将是其Z方向
get its forward vector, which will be its Z direction.
然后这取决于你的游戏是否是自上而下的
And then it depends on whether or maybe your game is top down,
也许它不是你的正向向量 在这种情况下它可能是你的Y向量
maybe it's not your forward vector, maybe it's your Y vector in that case.
但这将有效地给你--不仅是你有一个碰撞
But that will effectively give you-- not only that you've got a collision,
而且还能告诉你碰撞在哪里 这很好
but also tell you where the collision is too, which is nice.
我们在门户枪脚本中做到了这一点 我们称之为物理@光线广播
And we do that in the portal gun script where we call physics@raycast.
顺便说一下 这就是实际进行光线投射的函数
So this is the function, by the way, to actually do the ray cast.
在Unity中关于光线投射的有趣之处
The interesting thing about ray casting in Unity
它返回一个结构对象
is that it returns a struct object.
因此 您需要声明这个Hit对象 它
And so, you need to declare this hit object, which
会告诉你所有关于袭击的信息 比如在哪里
will tell you all the information about the hit, like where
它是 无论它是不是一开始就很受欢迎
it was, whether it was a hit to begin with,
它与之相撞的表面上的法线是什么 所以角度
and what the normal was on the surface that it collided with, so the angle
这种飞机就是从那里伸出来的
at which that sort of plane was projecting out.
然后 您可以使用位置和变换方向来调用物理@raycast
And then, you call physics@raycast with the position and a transform direction.
然后 你传进击出的球
And then, you pass in out hit.
所以Out很有趣 因为这是C Sharp的一种方式
So out is interesting because it is sort of C Sharp's way of allowing you
为某物返回多个值
to return multiple values to something.
所以Out将是一个物体 在这种情况下
So out is going to be an object, in this case,
这将是我们在这里宣布的光线投射的热门节目 对吗？
it's going to be our ray cast hit that we declared up here, right?
它是一个结构 它的recall只是一个变量集合 就像在C#中一样
Which is a struct, which recall is just a collection of variables like in C
或C++
or C++.
而Out Hit只是意味着通常我们将这些值传递给函数
And out hit just means that normally we pass in these values to the function,
他们不会被操控 对吧？
they don't get manipulated, right?
但是我们将这个变量作为out传递 它
But we pass in this variable as out, which
将允许此函数实际更改
will allow this function to actually change
该命中变量中的数据
the data inside this hit variable.
因此 结果就是从这一点开始
And so the result of that is hit from this point
Forward包含有关光线的所有信息
forward contains all of the information about the ray
我们刚刚触发的投射
cast that we just triggered.
当我们调用mathf.inifity时
And when we call mathf.inifity, that just
意味着光线投射到无限 直到永无止境
means ray cast to infinity, which is until forever and ever.
而联合显然不会无限地检查
And Unity obviously doesn't check infinitely
无论是什么东西与什么东西碰撞 它都会以正确的方式进行优化
whether something is colliding with something, it optimizes the right way.
但是 如果您不一定要指定i 则可以使用它
But you can use that just if you don't want to necessarily specify I
想在我面前检查两个单位或五个单位或一千个单位
want to check two units or five units or a thousand units front of me.
我想永远检查一下 看看它是否会相撞
I want to just check forever and see if it collides
在你的场景里有什么东西 对吗？
with something in your scene, right?
然后 正如你在这里看到的 一旦我们检测到碰撞
And then as you can see here once we have detected a collision,
我们播放传送门声音 我们得到正确的传送门
we play a portal sound, we get the right portal,
然后我们设置门户的变换和旋转
and then we set the portal's transform and rotation
基于命中点和旋转
based upon the hits point and rotation.
而这几乎就是枪击事件的全部内容
And that's pretty much all that's involved in shooting the gun.
你可以从这里看一看 如果你
And you can take a look through here if you
我想了解它是如何工作的 也许还想探索一下
want to get a sense of how it works, and maybe explore also
API的Physiics.raycast部分刚刚
the physics.raycast section of the API just
以了解它到底返回了什么 以及您可以用它做什么
to understand what exactly it returns and what you can do with it.
但在这种情况下 这就是我们如何使用
But in this case, this is how we're using
它可以检测我们是否与长城相交
it to detect whether we've intersected with the wall.
所以它可以与任何类型的网格相交
So it'll intersect with any sort of mesh.
然后 当它发生时 它会确切地告诉你它是如何做到的
And then when it does, it will tell you exactly how it did.
这就是光线投射
So that is what ray casting is.
雷·卡斯特罗对《沃尔芬斯坦》这样的老式游戏有另外一个名字
Ray casting has another name for like old school games like "Wolfenstein."
渲染的方法称为光线投射
The method of rendering was called ray casting
你可以从屏幕的每个像素产生一条光线
where you would generate a ray from every pixel of the screen
有效地 尽管它主要是屏幕上的每一行
effectively, although it was mostly just every line of the screen.
你只需上下看它在场景中相交的每一个地方
And you would just look up and down for everywhere it intersected in the scene,
然后在那里画一个纹理
and then just draw a texture there.
所以这将产生一个看起来像3D的世界
And so that would generate a world that looked 3D,
但你不能上下移动 因为它总是在产生
but you couldn't move up and down because it was always generating
所有的光线都完全向前
all the rays completely forward.
所以你被锁在两个轴上
And so you were locked onto two axis.
但是光线投射在Unity中是不同的
But ray casting is different in Unity.
光线投射只是从字面上投射光线
Ray casting is just literally casting a ray
在3D空间与它曾经的2D空间
in 3D space versus the sort of 2D space that it was
在《沃尔芬斯坦》这样的游戏中选角
casting in games like "Wolfenstein."
这是另一个从我们的门户投射光线的法线截图
Here's another screenshot of normals from our portals casting out rays.
我想看看我能不能找到一张“沃尔芬斯坦”的照片
And I want to look up and see if I can find a picture of what "Wolfenstein"
看起来像是
looked like.
我很肯定大多数人可能都熟悉 而不是新的
I'm pretty sure most folks are probably familiar with not the new one.
是啊 《沃尔芬斯坦3D》
Yeah, "Wolfenstein 3D."
这就是《沃尔芬斯坦》
So this was "Wolfenstein."
太老派了 但这种光线投射是不同的
So old school, but this sort of ray casting was different.
它基本上会从屏幕上的每一行上下发射射线
It would basically shoot rays from every single line of the screen up and down.
它会根据水平几何来检测--
And it would detect, based on the level geometry-- which
是非常简单的水平几何学
was very simple level geometry.
基本上只是那里有没有一堵墙 真的还是假的
It was just basically whether there was a wall there or not, true or false,
有点像2D图像
kind of like a 2D image.
它会根据它有多远来画
And it would draw, based on how far away it
就是 几何学中的那个点
was, that particular point of the geometry,
它只会在特定点绘制特定纹理的像素
it would just draw pixels from a specific texture at a specific point.
他们必须在纹理中的位置进行插补
And they had to interpolate where in the texture.
事情稍微复杂了一点
It was a little more complicated.
但如果你看到光线投射在这两种不同的意义上使用--
But in case you see ray casting used in those two different senses--
在老式游戏引擎的情况下 在
in the case of old school game engines, in the case
现代单位的光线投射 这就是涉及到的东西
of modern Unity sort of ray casting, that is what is involved in that.
简而言之 关于光线投射的任何问题
So any questions as to how in a nutshell the ray casting
在我们这个游戏的背景下工作吗？
works in the context of our game here?
观众：我们要用[INAUDIBLE]吗？
AUDIENCE: Are we going to be using the [INAUDIBLE]??
科尔顿·奥格登：所以不幸的是 没有
COLTON OGDEN: So unfortunately, no.
Oculus在Mac上不起作用
The Oculus does not work on Mac.
他们没有Mac支持
They do not have Mac support.
因此 我们无法让它的一个版本工作
And so we were unable to get a version of it working.
考虑到我们有多少时间 我们没有必要的交通工具
We don't have the means to necessarily transport given how much time we had.
现在 让VR在Unity中工作实际上非常容易
Now getting VR working in Unity is actually very easy.
如果我没记错的话 我只需要记住菜单就行了
If I recall correctly, I have to just remember the exact menu.
我之前就已经预料到了这一点
I had sort of anticipated talking about this before.
我想是播放器XR设置的问题
I think it's player XR settings.
是的 就是这样
Yeah, that's it is.
所以这是非常简单的
So it's incredibly easy.
如果你想在Unity中用VR玩游戏 而且你有一台开箱即用的PC
If you want to do a game in VR in Unity, and you have a PC, out of the box
很容易就能让它运转起来
is very easy just to get it working.
你所需要做的就是进入编辑项目设置 然后进入播放器
All you need to do is go to Edit Project Settings, and then go to Player.
然后在XR设置中--因此Unity已经设计了所有的VR AR设备
And then in the XR settings-- so Unity has deamed all of its VR AR stuff
作为XR
as XR.
然后点击此处支持的虚拟现实
And you click Virtual Reality Supported Here.
你有你的Oculus Rift或Vibe或任何插头
And you have your Oculus Rift or Vibe or whatever plugged in,
它可以在大门外的摄像头下工作
it'll just work with the camera right out of the gate.
所以这很容易
So it's pretty easy.
您可能需要在您的计算机上安装驱动程序
You may have to install drivers on your computer such
你的电脑知道你插了一台Oculus
that your computer knows that you have an Oculus plugged in,
但假设一切都准备好了 你的项目
but assuming that's all set up, your project
只需点击此复选框即可轻松完成
is as easy as just clicking this checkbox.
观众：这款耳机支持哪些耳机？
AUDIENCE: Which headsets does this support?
科尔顿·奥格登：全息镜头 Oculus Rift 还有我很确定的Vive
COLTON OGDEN: HoloLens, Oculus Rift, and I'm pretty sure the Vive.
90%肯定是万岁
90% sure the Vive.
我不是100% 不过我们可以在谷歌上搜索
I'm not 100%, we can Google it though.
让我们看看
Let's see.
团结5.
Unity 5.
观众：这些耳机有没有特别的开发者版本
AUDIENCE: Is there a special developer version of those headsets,
或者是[INAUDIBLE]？
or is it [INAUDIBLE]?
科尔顿·奥格登：看起来的确如此
COLTON OGDEN: It looks like it does.
看起来肯定是这样的 是的
It looks like it definitely does, yeah.
当然 VR Windows PC非常--
And of course, VR Windows PC is very--
我向你道歉
I apologize.
我完全认为进入Oculus在Mac上工作的课程
I totally thought going into the course that Oculus worked on a Mac.
但就在10月份 他们就像是
But as of even October, they were like it's not going
可以在任何MacBook上使用
to work on any MacBook ever released.
在PC上 不幸的是
So only on a PC, unfortunately.
也就是说 如果你有一台PC 超级容易工作
That said, if you do have a PC, super easy to get working.
看起来这实际上是一个很酷的教程
And it looks like this is actually a pretty cool tutorial.
我还没看过但我挺喜欢雷的
I haven't looked at this, but I tend to like Ray--
我不知道他是叫文德利希还是文德利希
I don't know if his name is Wenderlich or Wenderlich,
但他的游戏编程教程总体来说很不错
but he makes really good game programming tutorials in general.
因为我们碰巧在这里 如果你们好奇
So because we're co-incidentally here, if you guys are curious,
我真的很喜欢这个网站的基本教程的东西
I really like this website for basic tutorial stuff.
“难道 还有其他人回来吗？”
AUDIENCE: Are there other [INAUDIBLE] coming back?
你有Vive
You have Vive.
科尔顿·奥格登：我们有Vive
COLTON OGDEN: We have Vive.
关于Vive 你需要在天花板上安装摄像头
Well, the thing about Vive is you need to install ceiling mounted cameras
才能成功
in order for it to work.
所以这是一种出了方程
So that's kind of out of the equation.
我们有Gear VR 但我们需要将其导出到移动设备并进行测试
We have the Gear VR, but we would need to export it to mobile and test it.
我没想到它对麦克不起作用
I didn't anticipate it not working for Mac,
所以说起来有点晚
and so it kind of came up a bit late.
所以 都怪我
And so, it's on me.
我道歉
I apologize.
但是如果你在Oculus上做一个PC游戏 你需要一些帮助
But if you are doing a PC game in Oculus and you want some assistance,
我很乐意帮忙
I'm happy to help out.
它看起来很容易只是得到与默认FPS控制器的工作
It looks like it's very easy just to get working with the default FPS controller
相机
camera.
所以 如果你正在开发Oculus
So definitely reach out if you're developing Oculus
需要一些帮助
and need some assistance.
也许在我们下一个Unity课程中 我们可以有一个大型的VR日
Maybe for the our next Unity course, we can have a big sort of VR day
我们把所有的枪都带来了
where we bring in all the guns.
但是 是的
But, yeah.
回到射线铸造和我们刚刚谈论的
Back to ray casting and what we were just talking about.
根据你的旋转在z轴上发射一条射线 从中获取信息
Shooting a ray on your z-axis based on your rotation, get information from it,
然后我们要做的就是翻转传送门
and then sort of what we do is we flip the portal
根据撞击表面的旋转
based on the hit.rotation of the surface that we collided with.
这就是我们所做的所有光线投射
And that's effectively all the ray casting that we
需要担心的问题“
need to worry about for "Portal."
但《传送门》的实际制作可能是最有趣的部分
But the actual making of "Portal" is probably the most interesting part
这整个项目
of this whole project.
所以让我们继续 回到现在的模式
And so let's go ahead and go back into present mode.
因此 渲染纹理是我们开始做这件事的基本方式
So a rendered texture is the fundamental way at which we go about doing it.
要做到这一点有多种方法
And there are various ways to accomplish doing
它 一些在技术上更具挑战性的
it, some that are more technically challenging
而且看起来比其他人好多了
and look a lot nicer than others.
我只是做了一个简单的版本
I did a sort of simple version of it just
才能走出大门进行概念验证
to get to a proof of concept out of the gate.
但Unity只需设置一个简单的渲染纹理就很容易了
But Unity makes it really easy just to get a simple render texture up
还有奔跑
and running.
因此 回想一下 渲染的纹理只是Unity中的一个纹理
So a rendered texture is, recall, just a texture in Unity.
因此 它是一种资产 是您可以创建的Unity资产
So it's an asset, it's an Unity asset that you can create.
渲染纹理之间的差异
The difference between a rendered texture
以及您可能从Photoshop或Gimp导入的纹理
and a texture that you might have imported from like Photoshop or Gimp,
渲染的纹理可以渲染到
is that a rendered texture can be rendered to.
通常 它用于渲染到它的相机之类的东西
And typically, this is used for things like cameras being rendered to it.
不过 据我所知 你可以给它渲染任何东西
Although, from what I understand, you can render anything to it.
因此 您也可以通过这种方式创建程序纹理
So you can create procedural textures this way as well.
但在这个例子中 我们基本上是
But in this example here, we're essentially
创造了一个我们正在观看的屏幕
creating a screen into which we're looking
从我们另一个传送门的角度来看 对吗？
at the viewpoint of our other portal, right?
从它的前进方向
From its forward direction.
所以我们可以看到一旦我们走出传送门会是什么样子
So we can see what it will look like once we walk out of the portal
然后进入下一个区域
and go into the next area.
如果你想下载这些幻灯片 我在幻灯片里有一些
So I have some in the slides, if you want to download the slides.
他们来了
They're here.
您可以确切地看到如何创建渲染纹理
You can see exactly how to create a render texture,
因此 从字面上讲 只需创建并渲染纹理 即可创建渲染纹理
so literally just create and then render texture that creates a render texture.
这些是我用于实际渲染纹理的设置
These are the settings that I used for the actual render texture.
那么 我们认为 如果我们使用低分辨率渲染 会发生什么
So what would happen, do we think, if we use like a low res render
质感 只是逻辑上的？
texture, just logically?
或者假设我的渲染纹理是200 x 200像素？
Or let's say my rendered texture was like 200 pixels by 200 pixels?
我们游戏的分辨率是10EDP吗？
And the resolution of our game is like 10 EDP?
观众：这会被夸大吗？
AUDIENCE: Will that just be blown up?
科尔顿·奥格登：它不会被炸毁 因为什么
COLTON OGDEN: It won't be blown up because what
我们要做的就是拿一个网状物 然后把纹理贴在上面
we're doing is we're taking a mesh, and we're affixing the texture to it.
所以它只会缩放以填充网格
So it'll just scale to fill the mesh.
但是渲染后会是什么样子呢？
But what will it look like when it's rendered?
因为它要渲染200像素的纹理
Because it's rendering a 200 pixel texture.
它会变尖 看起来很恶心
It'll apixelate it, it'll look really nasty.
为了解决这个问题 通常你会
And so in order to fix that problem, typically what you'll
一个聪明的方法是在运行时动态地计算出
do-- a smart way to do it, would be to dynamically figure out at runtime
你的游戏的分辨率是多少
what's the resolution of your game, right?
如果它要以高达4K的各种分辨率呈现
If it's going to be rendered in various resolutions up to 4K,
可能会降到720 p
maybe down to 720p.
然后创建游戏大小的渲染纹理
And then create a render texture that is the size of your game.
通过这样做 它将确保无论你的决心是什么
And then by doing that, it will ensure that no matter what your resolution is,
它的像素比例总是1：1 即使你离它很近 对吗？
it will always be 1:1 pixel ratio, even if you're right up close to it, right?
它会填满整个屏幕
It will fill up your whole screen.
在这种情况下 我们采用了一种更简单的方法
In this case, we went for a simpler method
所以我们不需要对渲染的纹理做任何动态的实例化
so we didn't have to do any dynamic instantiation of the rendered texture,
你完全可以做到
which you can absolutely do.
这是一种更稳健的方式
And it is the more robust way to do it.
但在这个例子中 我选择了1024 x1024
But in this case, I just chose 1024x1024,
认为这足以用于演示目的
figuring that that was going to be good enough for demonstration purposes.
大多数其他的设置--
And most of these other settings--
我相信实际上所有这些其他的设置都是完全
I believe actually all these other settings are completely
默认渲染纹理设置
default render texture settings.
唯一改变的是默认情况下是256 x256
The only ones that changed were this is 256x256 by default,
它看起来真的是像素化的和肮脏的 特别是当
and it just looks really pixelated and nasty, especially when
你就离它很近
you're right up close to it.
然后我们要做的就是
And then all we need to do--
所以一旦我们在场景中创建了渲染纹理 在我们的资产中--
so once we've created a rendered texture in our scene, in our assets--
所以在这里 我将去纹理
so here, I'm going to go to textures.
这是我展示所有纹理的地方 无论它们是
This is where I'm showing all my textures, whether they're
渲染纹理或不
rendered textures or not.
我有这两个渲染纹理在这里
I have these two render textures here.
所以 这些是默认的
And so, these are by default, they're not
会被映射到任何东西 因为它们只是空的渲染纹理
going to be mapped to anything because they're just empty rendered textures.
我们已经有效地分配了他们
We've effectively allocated them and said
稍后会有一些东西呈现给它们 但现在它们只是空的
something will be rendering to these later, but for now they're just empty,
有占位符对吧
there's placeholders, right?
它们就像是空白屏幕 但电视还没有打开
They're like blank screens, but the TV hasn't been turned on yet.
为了实际渲染到它们 我们使用任何相机
In order to actually render to them, we go into whatever camera
我们要将其渲染到渲染纹理
we want to render it to, render to the render texture.
因为我们有效地利用了这些渲染纹理
Because we're effectively taking these render textures,
我们要把摄像机的视角渲染到他们身上 对吗？
and we're rendering a camera view onto them, right?
每个入口后面都有一个摄像头 从后面向外看
Each of the portals has a camera behind it looking out from it.
所以我们想要从摄像机的角度来看
And so we want to take that camera's view,
我们想把它渲染到另一个传送门的脸上
and we want to render that onto the other portal's face.
另一个门户的渲染纹理、纹理
The other portal's render texture, the texture
我们要把它放在上面
that we're going to put onto it.
所以 我们所要做的就是说 “这是我的橙色入口
And so, all we need to do is say, "Here's my orange portal.
我的相机在这里
I have my camera here.
每个摄像头都有一个刚出大门的目标纹理
Every camera has a target texture just right out the gate."
所以你可以说 “好的 我要用我的橙色入口纹理
So you can just say, "OK, I'm going to take my orange portal texture,
我的已实例化的渲染纹理
my render texture that has been instantiated
因此它知道它将能够接收输入源
so it knows that it's going to be able to receive an input source.
我只需点击并将其拖到那里
And I'm going to just click and drag it there."
事情就是这么简单
And it's that simple.
现在 当你运行游戏时 你会注意到你的渲染纹理
Now whenever you run the game, you'll notice that your render texture
最新消息
updates.
我不确定它是否在检查员中实时更新
I'm not sure if it updates in real time in the inspector,
但如果你把它展示给一个--
but it renders if you're showing it on to a--
是的 它不会呈现在探长身上
yeah, it doesn't render in the inspector,
但如果您将其粘贴到任何其他曲面上 它将会更新
but it will update if you affix it to any other surface.
所以 我们要做的就是把它贴上
And so, what we're doing is we're affixing it
到与每个门户相关联的网格
to the meshes that are associated with each portal.
詹姆斯 你有问题吗？
James, did you have a question?
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
你是怎么做这个质地的？
How did you make the texture?
科尔顿·奥格登：哦 当然 渲染纹理？
COLTON OGDEN: Oh sure, the render texture?
所以我只需点击鼠标右键 然后去创建
So I just right click, and then I go to create,
然后在这里渲染纹理
and then to render texture right here.
这将为您提供设置所需的大部分设置
And that will give you most of the settings that you need to get up
并带着它运行 你可以将它分配给相机
and running with it, and you can assign it to a camera.
但重要的是要考虑你的决心
But the important thing is do consider your resolution
用于渲染纹理
for your render texture.
确保它足够高 以便您的游戏不会在以下情况下看起来像素化
Make sure that it's high enough so that your game won't look pixelated when
你正近距离地看着它
you're looking at it pretty close up.
观众：就这么简单吗？
AUDIENCE: So it's as easy as that?
你只是制作纹理 然后拖动相机？
You just make the texture and then drag the camera?
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
COLTON OGDEN: Yup.
是的
Yup.
这将在两者之间建立起一种联系
And what that will do is create a link between the two
所以摄像机拍到的任何东西 都不再是
so that anything the camera sees, it's no longer
将渲染到场景或其他什么地方
going to be rendering to the scene or anything
就像 它只会渲染到纹理上
like, it's just going to render to the texture.
事实上 我认为你可以把它与现场和纹理联系起来
And actually, I think you can run it to the scene and the texture,
但这些根本不会渲染到场景中
but these aren't rendering to the scene at all.
渲染到场景的唯一角色是第一人称角色
The only one rendering to the scene is the first person character
因为它是默认的摄像头 主摄像头
because it's the default camera, main camera.
观众：如果将分辨率设置为[INAUDIBLE]会发生什么情况
AUDIENCE: What happens if you set the resolution to [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：如果分辨率太高
COLTON OGDEN: If it's too high of a resolution,
它只是要压缩 以适应网格 无论它贴在哪里
it's just going to compress to fit the mesh, whatever it's affixed to.
而且您可能会遇到性能问题
And you'll probably run into performance problems.
但它不会破裂
But it's not going to break.
嗯
Yeah.
因为你的决心并不一定会对
Because your resolution doesn't really have an effect necessarily on whatever
在你的游戏世界里 这不会引起任何问题
is in your game world, and that doesn't cause any issues.
它会被插补
It gets interpolated.
Unity只会计算如何将其渲染到屏幕上 对吗？
Unity will just calculate how to render it to the screen, right?
一般来说 游戏纹理的分辨率非常高
Game textures, generally, are very high resolution,
像4K纹理经常被使用 即使你运行你的游戏在1080p
like 4K textures are often used, even if you're running your game in 1080p.
游戏引擎可能会对其进行优化
And a game engine will probably optimize it
并对纹理进行下采样 这样它实际上就像是1080p的纹理
and down sampled the texture so that it is like actually a 1080p texture.
你不是想要计算更多 画出比你需要更多的东西
And you're not trying to calculate more, draw more than you need to.
但团结会为你解决这一问题
But Unity will figure that out for you.
你不必担心这一点
You don't have to worry about that.
但没错 这就是渲染纹理的含义
But yeah, that's what a render texture is.
这就是我们创造这种错觉的方式
And that's how we are creating this illusion.
记住 游戏中的一切都是幻觉
Remember, everything in the game is an illusion.
在这种情况下 因为纹理是平坦的
In this case, because the textures are flat
而且没有视角修正 你
and there's no perspective correction, you
我可以看到它是一种质地 即使它从很远的地方看起来有点令人信服
can see that it's a texture, even if it is slightly convincing from far away.
就像从远处看 它实际上看起来--
Like from far away it actually kind of looks--
我是说 我不知道它看起来是否真实
I mean, I don't know if it necessarily looks real.
我是说 有点像 对吧？
I mean, it kind of does, right?
从这里 很难说
From here, it's hard to tell.
从这里看我们好像要去另一个房间 对吧？
And from here it kind of looks like we're going into another room, right?
我就像这样--嗯 那是破碎的墙
I go like that-- well, that's the broken wall.
当我像那样走的时候 对吗？
When I go like that, right?
那里有一个传送门 看起来像是
There's a portal there, and it kind of looks like it's
一个真实的房间
a real room that we're walking through.
只是一个决议
It's just a resolution.
但我们所做的只是画出摄像机的视角
But all we're doing is we're just drawing a camera's view
实时地投射到纹理上
onto that texture in real time.
如果你注意到了 当我们移动的时候 我们可以看到枪
And if you notice, when we move, we can see the gun.
所以我们可以看到它是实时渲染的
So we can see that it's rendering it in real time.
这就是渲染纹理的力量
And that's the power of a render texture.
这将允许你做各种各样的事情
And this will allow you to do all kinds of things.
你可以在你的游戏里有电视屏幕
You can have like TV screens in your game
渲染场景的另一部分
that are rendering another part of your scene.
很明显像这样的例子
Obviously an example like this where you have
一个通往另一个区域的入口
a portal looking into another area.
现在如果你用透视校正
Now if you apply a perspective correction
你的摄像机可以跟踪球员的位置
to this whereby your camera actually tracks where your player's position is
相对于门户 您可以实现更可信的外观
relative to the portal, you can accomplish a much more believable look.
实际上你可以让它看起来像是你在观察另一个领域
And you can actually make it seem as if you're looking into another area
因为摄像机是随着你的播放器移动的
because the camera is literally moving with your player.
所以摄像头--比如它捕捉的东西
So the cameras-- like the stuff that it's capturing
是实时变化的 不仅仅是你的角色模型
is going to be changing in real time, not only just your character's model,
对吧？
right?
实际的角度会改变 因此 透视是正确的
The actual angle is going to change and therefore, be perspective correct.
有一个很棒的教程
And there's an awesome tutorial that I'm going
链接到幻灯片中 幻灯片会告诉你如何去做
to link to in the slides that'll show you how to go about doing that.
它真的很棒
And it's really awesome.
这就是它最终的样子
And so this is what it ends up looking like.
这是在我改变之前
This is actually before I changed--
其中一个入口的摄像头角度略有偏移
one of the portals had a slightly offset camera angle.
所以你可以看到这里有点像
So you can see here this is like a little bit
比这个高 尽管它们应该是一样的
higher than this one is, even though they should be exactly the same.
但现在修好了
But it's fixed now.
所以纹理遮罩--哦 有什么问题吗？
So texture masking-- oh, any questions about any of that
在我们讨论纹理遮罩之前的处理过程？
process before we talk about texture masking?
好的 所以纹理遮罩基本上就是这个过程
OK, so texture masking is basically the process.
因此 如果我们只取一个平面 并在其上添加渲染纹理
So if we just take a plane and we put a render texture onto it,
看起来就是这样
that's what it looks like.
它看起来就像是个正方形
It just looks like it's just a square.
如果你想要一种方形的门户外观 这可能会很好地发挥作用
And this could work fine if you want sort of a square portal look,
你不需要做任何额外的工作
you don't have to do any extra work.
但如果你想要一个圆圈 你真的不能
But if you want a circle, you can't really
像一个圆形的普通物体一样创造 那并不真正存在
create like a circle shaped plain object, that doesn't really exist.
即使是这样 也不会有效率
And even if it did, it wouldn't be efficient,
尤其是如果你想要一个非常平滑的平面 因为所有的东西
especially if you want a very smooth plane because everything
是三角形和多边形 对吗？
is triangles and polygons, right?
所以如果你有一个圆圈 它将是
So if you have a circle, it's going to be
其中一些呈扇形分布 特别是分辨率非常高的多边形
a bunch of these fanned out polygons, especially very high res
像这样围成一个圈
circle like one of these.
这是一个非常高的分辨率循环
That's a very high res circle.
创建一个看起来像那样的面并不是最佳方法
Making a polygon that looks like that is not an optimal way
去解决这个问题 对吗？
to go about solving that problem, right?
解决问题的更理想的方法
The much more optimal way to go about solving
该问题将是指定某些纹理的特定像素
that problem would be to designate certain pixels of some texture
作为我们想要读取的像素 然后是某些其他像素
as being pixels that we want to read, and then certain other pixels
不是我们想要读取的像素
being not pixels that we want to read.
因此 产生最终的图像 然后放到几何体上 对吗？
And therefore, produce the final image that gets put onto a geometry, right?
因此 我们最终要做的是首先创建一个图像
And so, what we end up doing is creating an image first.
所以就是这张图片 它很难被看到
So it's this image, which is kind of hard to see,
但这只是一种简单的--
but it's just a simple sort of--
你能从那里看到吗？
can you see from there?
不 你可以的
Yeah, you can.
所以这只是一个简单的椭圆形 对吗？
So it's just a simple oval, right?
这正是我们希望我们的门户看起来像的形状
It's the exact shape that we want our portal to look like.
白色的像素是我们要渲染的像素
And the pixels that are white are the pixels that we're going to render,
黑色的像素是我们不想渲染的像素
and the pixels that are black are the pixels that we don't want to render.
我们希望有效地将它们视为纯零阿尔法
We want to consider those as pure zero alpha effectively.
使用一个很棒的着色器 你可以得到
And using a awesome shader that you can get
在Unity网页上轻松免费--这只是一个遮罩着色器
for free just easily on the Unity web page-- this is just a masking shader.
我不擅长编写着色器 但它的作用是
And I'm not great at writing shaders, but what this does
正在关闭照明
is turns lighting off.
首先 如果我们将照明应用于我们的门户会发生什么？
First of all, what happens if we have lighting applied to our portals?
这看起来会有点奇怪 对吧？
It's going to look a little weird, right?
你会在你的门户上投下阴影
You're going to get shadows cast on your portals
这说不通 因为我们有效地
and that doesn't make sense because we're effectively
应该是在调查另一个地方 另一个地区
supposed to be looking into another place, another area.
所以我们有阴影投射到我们的东西上
So we have shadows that are being cast onto our thing,
我们实际上就像在我们的门户上看到了一扇玻璃门 对吗？
we're effectively like almost seeing like a glass door on our portal, right?
它在某种程度上打破了这种错觉
It sort of breaks the illusion.
所以灯光应该关掉
So lighting should be off.
很多这样的事情我不是百分之百的 因为我不是
A lot of these things I'm not 100% on because I'm not
很擅长编写着色器 但它是一个非常简单、容易的着色器
great at writing shaders, but it's a very simple, easy shader
你可以从Unity的网页上抓取
that you can grab off of the Unity web page.
我想我把最下面的url剪掉了
I think I clipped the url here at the very bottom.
但我是从Unity的网页上拿来的
But I grabbed it off of the Unity web page.
它所做的就是在你的材料上添加第二幅图像
And all it does is it adds onto your material this second image here,
它被放大了一点 因为Unity制作了任何质地
and it gets blown up a little bit because Unity makes any texture
基本上可以应用于您的任何纹理
that you apply to basically any texture you
像放进一个图像选择器就会被做成正方形
put into like an image selector will get made into a square shape.
我们的形象也不是正方形的
And our image is not square shaped.
但它所做的是 当您传入此图像时
But what this does is when you pass in this image, which
被称为煤遮罩 它基本上会将这两个图像结合起来
is called a coaling mask, it will basically combine the two images
然后抵消掉上面任何黑色的像素
and then cancel out any of the pixels that are black on this.
它将有效地将黑白添加到纹理的Alpha中
It'll effectively add the black and white to the alpha of the texture
像素 对吧？
pixels, right?
所以你实际上可以把其中的一些变成灰色
So you can actually make some of these gray
然后他们会产生让它变得半透明的效果
and then they'll have the effect of sort of making it half transparent.
但在这种情况下 我只选择了全透明和全硬255阿尔法
But in this case, I only went with full transparent and full hard 255 alpha.
因此 我们得到了门户网站的清晰轮廓
So we get sort of a crisp outline for our portals.
这就是你如何将一个基本的椭圆形组合在一起
And that's how you end up putting together a basic sort of oval shape
在只是一个平坦的网状物上
on something that is just a flat mesh.
你可以在任何事情上做到这一点
And you can do this with anything.
任何时候你需要去掉一个细节
Anytime you need to take away a detail that
会让制作网格变得非常困难 或者做一些非常酷的效果
would make making a mesh extremely difficult or doing really cool effects,
为它制作一个面具通常要容易得多
it's often just a lot easier to create a mask for it
然后使用正确的着色器 该着色器应该具有该遮罩
and then use the right shader that's meant to have that mask.
然后只需按你需要的方式操纵它
And then just manipulate that however you need to.
同样 着色器的链接在这里
And again, the link here for the shader is here.
然后你可以用它做任何你想做的事情
And then you can use this for pretty much anything you want.
最终的结果是我们从一个正方形门户
End result of that is we go from having a square portal
到一个椭圆形的入口
to an elliptical portal.
太棒了
So pretty nice.
我不用坐飞机 但它并不是真的
I didn't have to use a plane, but it doesn't really
使用其他任何东西都是有意义的 因为使用立方体可以创建深度
make sense to use anything else because using a cube would create depth.
我们不希望门户有任何深度 真的
We don't want the portal to have any depth, really.
只是应该是一个平坦的表面
It's just should be a flat surface.
然后当我们经历它的时候 它应该
And then when we go through it, it should just
将我们传送到另一个表面 让它看起来像是无缝的
teleport us to the other surface to make it look sort of seamless.
我不认为有任何其他的几何学选择
I don't think there's any other choice of geometry that
对于这个用例来说是有意义的
makes sense for this use case.
观众：你不会只是把一个圆柱体压平 然后[INAUDIBLE]
AUDIENCE: You wouldn't just make a cylinder flat and have [INAUDIBLE]
在上面投射吗？
project on it?
科尔顿·奥格登：不 我可能不会
COLTON OGDEN: No, I probably wouldn't.
让圆柱体变平 然后投射出来 而且没有深度
To make a cylinder flat and project it and have no depth on it,
你仍然可以看到它上面的戒指
you would be able to still see the rings on it.
纹理处理也要稍微复杂一些
And also texturing that is a little bit more complicated
因为您必须对蒙版和常规纹理进行UV贴图
because you'd have to UV map both your mask and your regular texture
因为默认情况下 它会包装得很奇怪
onto that because by default it's going to wrap it weird.
这只是一个平面 所以无论映射到它的纹理是什么
This is just a plane, so whatever you texture map onto it
将会是完全平坦的
is going to be completely flat.
但圆柱体会把它包裹在四面八方
But a cylinder is going to wrap it around all sides,
它看起来会有点时髦
and it's going to look a little bit funky.
我想理论上你可以用圆柱体来装它
I suppose in theory you could use a cylinder for it,
但我认为这将是一项巨大的工作
but I think would be a tremendous amount of work.
我认为这不会像让它起作用那样容易
I don't think it would be anywhere near as easy as getting it to work
只有一个平面或一个网状物
with just a flat plane or a mesh.
不过 这个想法很有趣
Interesting idea, though.
我猜理论上你可以创造一个圆柱体
I guess you could theoretically create a cylinder
如果你想成为连接两个世界的桥梁
if you wanted to like a bridge between two worlds
一端是入口 另一端是入口
and have one end be one portal and one end be another portal
然后能够在它们之间行走
and then be able to walk between them.
这是一个很酷的想法 也许你可以做到这一点
That's a cool idea, maybe you can make that work.
但我认为 对于这一点 飞机是正确的方式去
But I think for this, the plane is the right way to go.
还有什么问题吗
Any more questions as to how that works?
好吧
All right.
我们现在来谈谈心灵传输
So we'll talk about teleporting now.
所以瞬移很容易
So teleporting is pretty easy.
我们真正需要做的就是创建一个网格碰撞器
All we really need to do is just create a mesh collider
在传送门网格上 橙色的传送门和蓝色的传送门
on the portal mesh, the orange portal and the blue portal.
这个网格碰撞器是一个触发器
And then that mesh collider is a trigger and it
检测到与其他物体的碰撞 我们可以在触发器上定义 输入
detects a collision with something else, we can just define on trigger, enter.
这样我们就能传送对撞机
And then with that, we can teleport the collider
其他门户网站的位置
other to the other portals location.
所以每个入口 这是入口的组成部分
So every portal, this is the portal component,
它有一个链接的入口 因为我们需要知道在哪里传送
it has a linked portal because we need to know where to teleport
把玩家带到另一个入口
the player to the other portal.
所以我们需要一个对它的transform的引用
So we need to have a reference to its transform.
它是否活跃是因为如果我们允许自己
Whether it's active because if we allow ourselves
传送到另一个传送门 然后在另一个传送门之间来回传送
to teleport to another portal and another portal back and forth
没有任何约束 你认为会发生什么？
without any restraints, what do you think is going to happen?
无限循环
Infinite loop.
我们就得到了一种无限的奇怪的闪烁效果
We just get an infinite sort of weird flickering effect.
因此 您需要在两个门户上有效地设置切换开关
So you need to effectively have a toggle switch on both portals
说我一进入传送门就不能
and say as soon as I enter a portal, I should not
能够瞬间移动回到里面
be able to teleport back into it.
一旦我传送到另一个入口
And as soon as I teleport to another portal,
我应该也无法瞬移进去
I should not be able to teleport into it either.
但是一旦你离开了传送门 你应该可以传送回去
But once you exit the portal, you should be able to teleport back into it.
因此 我们实际上进入了一个入口
And so, what that effectively does is we enter a portal,
它就会被标记为不可传送
it gets flagged as not teleportable.
我们被传送到另一个入口
We get teleported to the other portal.
一旦发生这种情况 这个入口现在可以传送到
As soon as that happens, this portal can now be teleported into,
我们所在的这个传送门被标记为不可传送
this portal that we're standing in is now flagged as not teleportable.
然后我们走出它 我们被允许传送回来
And then we walk out of it and we're allowed to teleport back
分成两个部分
into that one and the other one.
所以实际上有一个开关操作
So there's effectively an on off operation
你必须适当地平衡
that you have to balance appropriately.
实际的“门户”游戏稍微复杂一些
The actual "Portal" game is a little more complicated
因为它们允许你在两个入口之间走进去
because they allow you to walk in between portals.
这并没有深入到那种程度的细节
This does not go into that level of detail,
这是一个需要解决的更复杂的问题
and it's a more complicated problem to solve.
这个例子只是假设你走进一个门户
This example just assumes that you walk into a portal,
你可以把它传送到另一端 没有中间状态
you can teleport it out the other end, and there's no in-between state.
实际上 如果你在两个入口之间
And actually, if you're in-between two portals,
有一个几何体的复制 Valve将在他们的演讲中谈到
there's a replication of geometry, which Valve will talk about in their talk
我认为这将是非常有趣的
as well, which I think will be very interesting.
因为如果你在一个传送门中间看另一个传送门
Because if you look into another portal while you're in the middle of a portal,
你想在那个门户里看到你自己
you want to be able to see yourself in that portal,
在进入和离开那个传送门的中途
halfway in and out of that portal.
所以有很多有趣的考虑
So there is a lot of interesting considerations
获得非常可信的门户系统
for getting very believable portal systems,
但我们的是一个非常简单的例子
but ours is a very simple illustration.
因此 这个切换功能就是我所要做的
And so, this toggle function is all that I
必须切换该功能的开启和关闭功能
have to toggle the function's on and off capability.
它只是门户活动 而不是门户活动
And all it is just portal active is not portal active,
而这只会颠覆这面旗帜
and that just flips that flag.
这超级简单
It's super easy.
在触发器进入时 我们有效地兑现了x轴和z轴上的头寸x
On trigger enter, we effectively cash our position x on the x and z-axis,
所以我们不旋转它是因为当我们旋转我们的x
so we don't rotate it because when we rotate our x
和z在第一人称控制器上
and z on the first person controller by default,
它导致了一些非常奇怪的错误行为 基于
it causes some really weird buggy behavior based on the way
FPS控制器工作正常
that the FPS controller works.
所以我所要做的就是选择这些职位
So all I do is I just cast those positions,
然后在y轴上旋转
and then make a rotation on the y-axis.
这将为我们省去你将得到的奇怪的颠倒效应
And that'll save us that weird going topsy turvy effect that you'll get.
如果默认情况下使用FPS控制器 并且确实在其上执行旋转
If you use the FPS controller by default and you do perform rotations on it,
你会注意到这一点
you'll notice this.
所以我还没有时间深入挖掘如何修复它
So I haven't had the time to dig in depth as to how to fix it,
但这是我能够修复它的方法
but this is the way that I was able to fix it.
至少在这个例子中 只允许您自己
For this example, at least, only allow yourself
在y方向上旋转 这是你看起来相对的方向
to rotate on the y direction, which is where you're looking relative
到地平面
to the ground plane.
这将允许我们根据位置进行旋转
And that will allow us to rotate based on where
我们正在离开传送门 至少在上下的墙上
we're exiting the portal, at least on the walls that are going up and down
然后产生那种令人信服的效果
and then have that sort of believable effect.
它不允许我们从上面跳下进入一个入口
It doesn't allow us to jump down into a portal from up above
然后看到我们从另一个入口下来 那个入口
and see us coming down from the other portal, which
令人遗憾的是 这是一个很酷的效果 但它确实允许我们在大多数情况下
is a cool effect unfortunately, but it does allow us of to get most of the way
那里
there.
因此 我们将我们的位置设置为另一个门户的位置
And so, we set our position to the other portal's position
和我们的轮换 但只有y
and our rotation, but only the y.
我们得到y 然后我们在这里用我们球员的欧拉角来表示它
We get the y, and then we said it here using euler angles on our players
变形
transform.
然后是我创建的一个函数
And then there's a function that I created
称为鼠标重置 它实际上只是再次调用init
called mouse reset, which effectively just calls init again
关于FPS控制器在相机和播放器上的旋转
on the FPS controller's rotation on the camera and the player.
然后 这有点像你需要的黑客攻击 以便--
And then, that's sort of like the hack that you need in order to--
许多怪异之处之所以存在
the reason that a lot of the weirdness exists
是因为玩家控制器兑现了它的轮换信息
is because the player controller cashes its rotation information.
因此 如果您在FPS控制器上执行旋转
And so if you perform a rotation on your FPS controller
用手 而不是让它发生在鼠标上
by hand as opposed to allowing it to happen with the mouse,
它将立即将其重置回其先前的位置和旋转
it will immediately reset it back to its prior position and rotation.
其效果是当我们从一个门户传送到另一个门户时--
Which has the effect of when we teleport from one portal to another--
即使我们设置了旋转方向
even though we set our direction of rotation
在外面朝向入口所面对的方向
to be outside going in the direction of where the portal is facing,
我们最终得到了与进入传送门相同的旋转
we end up having the same rotation that we did entering the portal.
因此 我们最终走出门户往往只是倒退
So we end up coming out of portals often just backwards.
因此 这只是第一人称控制者的一个限制
And so, that's just a limitation of the first person controller,
但您可以通过调用鼠标重置来修复该问题 该函数
but you can fix that by calling mouse reset, which is a function that
本质上只是再次调用init
essentially just calls init again.
它是FPS控制器的鼠标外观对象的一部分
Which init is part of the FPS controller's mouse look object.
我不会太详细地谈论它 因为它是
I won't go too much into detail about it just because it's
有点晦涩难懂 如果你想看看里面的源代码
a little bit arcane and the source codes in there if you want to take a look
并涉足其中
and dabble with it.
但有效地阻止了它缓存其旋转信息
But effectively, preventing it from caching its rotation information
只需对其进行硬设置 然后调用鼠标
and just hard setting it, and then recalling the mouse
查看init函数 该函数执行旋转的实际设置
look init function, which does the actual setting of the rotation
在摄像机和播放器上
on the camera and the player.
有点奇怪 但那是Unity的FPS控制器
A little bit weird, but that's Unity's FPS controller,
这就是其他人说要解决的问题
and that's how other people are saying to fix it.
所以你可以使用你自己的 你可以创建你自己的FPS控制器
So you could roll your own, you can create your own FPS controller
并可能阻止这种情况的发生
and probably prevent this from happening.
但如果你想使用常规的FPS控制器
But if you want to use the regular FPS controller,
这就是那里的限制
that's the limitation there.
但它大部分都起作用了 看起来相当不错
But it's mostly working and it looks pretty good.
多花点时间 我们可能会让它看起来更好
Some more time on it, and we could probably make it look even better.
但就目前而言 我认为这是件好事
But for now, I think it's good.
所以这就是心灵传送
So that's teleporting.
设定好你的位置 然后设定你的y旋转
Set your position, and then set your y rotation,
覆盖FPS控制器的默认旋转缓存
override the FPS controller's default rotation caching,
我们可以走进这个入口 然后立即走出这个入口
and we can walk in this portal and then instantly walk out this portal.
这就是我们所看到的
And that's what we see.
简而言之 对于这是如何运作的 有什么问题吗？
So any questions as to how sort of this works in a nutshell?
或者可能是我们门户中的任何代码？
Or maybe any of the code here in our portal?
好的
All right.
因此 一个更好的门户版本 至少在呈现方面是这样的
So a much better version of the portal, at least from the rendering side,
这个视频在这里吗
is this video here.
所以是布拉克西斯
So it's Braxis.
太好了 他把事情解释得很好
So good he explains things very well.
他的视频质量非常高
He's got a very high quality to his videos.
他创建了一系列的Unity教程
He creates a bunch of Unity tutorials.
在这种情况下 他创建了一个门户
And in this case, he created a portal that
使用了一个有趣的着色器 只会
used an interesting shader that will only
渲染除几何体以外的所有对象 并将其渲染到平面上 在这种情况下 该平面
render everything but geometry and also onto a plane, in which case this plane.
并且做我之前提到的播放器的相机插补
And does the camera interpolation of the player that I alluded to before,
这让我们能够真正拥有--
which allows us to actually have--
所以现在这是两个不同的世界
so these are two separate worlds in tandem right now.
所以这里有一个红色的世界 然后这个相机
So there's this red world here, and then this camera
正着眼于一个完全不同的绿色世界
is looking at a completely different green world that's
在远方完全出发了
completely set off in the distance.
这是完全相同的几何图形 但完全是绿色的
That's the exact same geometry, but completely colored green
而不是红色
as opposed to red.
如果你透过这里看 它是完全无缝的
And if you look through here, it's just completely seamless
而且穿行是完全无缝的
and the walk through is completely seamless.
他详细介绍了他是如何完成这一切的
And he goes into detail as to how he accomplished all of this,
如果你好奇的话
if you're curious.
他还为您提供了可以免费使用的着色器
And he provides you the shader that you can use for free.
所以 如果你对此感兴趣 一定要检查一下
So definitely check that out if that's of interest.
视频中有一个链接
There's a link there in the video.
以下是他在YouTube上的系列节目的链接
And here's a link to his YouTube series.
我把其中的一些放在了闲置状态 因为有人要了一些人工智能视频
I put some of these in the slack because somebody requested some AI videos.
他有一堆不同的人工智能视频
And he has a bunch of different AI videos
还有很多其他很酷的剧集
and a bunch of other really cool series.
所以 如果你好奇的话 你可以看看这个
So you can take a look at that, if curious.
而“门户”最好的版本显然就是门户本身
And the best version of "Portal" obviously is the portal itself.
Dave Kircher和Tejeev Kohli是Valve的员工
And Dave Kircher and Tejeev Kohli are employees involved at Valve
为《门户网站》工作的人 他们将于5月2日来到这里
who worked on "Portal," and they'll be here on May 2
就所有技术方面的事情做一次演讲
to give a talk as to all of the technical sort of things that
在幕后 与渲染和物理有关
went behind the scenes and related to rendering and physics
只是得到了一种可信和美好的感觉
and just getting a believable and good feeling
体验实际打磨过的最终游戏《门户》
experience with "Portal" for the actual polished final game
这就是我们所说的
that we're talking about.
所以如果你好奇的话一定要来听那个演讲
So definitely come to that talk if you're curious.
我们要休息一下 然后一回来
We're going to take a break, and then as soon as we come back,
我们要谈一谈一些新工具
we're going to talk a little bit about some new tools
Unity发布了名为ProBuilder和ProGrids的产品
that Unity has released called ProBuilder and ProGrids.
我们会讨论作业的问题
And we'll talk about the assignment.
这将是它的50加元
And that will be it for GD 50.
好了 欢迎回来
All right, welcome back.
这是第十课
This is Lecture 10.
所以我们在休息前谈到了《门户》 我们谈到了光线投射
So we talked about "Portal" before the break, we talked about ray casting.
我们谈到了渲染纹理 它们是什么
We talked about render textures, what those are,
在统一中制作这些是多么容易
how easy it is to make those in Unity.
我们讨论了如何给我们的第一人称控制员一把枪
We talked about how to give our first person controller a gun
这样我们就可以环顾四周 看起来就像拿着武器一样
so that we could actually look around and look as if we're holding a weapon.
我们讨论了门户本身 以及如何掩盖渲染
We talked about the portals themselves, how we're masking out the render
应用于平面的纹理 以及每个纹理后面如何有摄影机
texture as applied to a plane, and how each of those has a camera behind it
这样它就可以呈现从门户在方向上发出的内容
so that it can render what is going out from the portal in the direction
它所面对的
that it's facing.
我们现在要离开“门户网站” 谈谈
We're going to deviate from "Portal" now, and talk
关于ProBuilder和ProGrids 这两个工具
about ProBuilder and ProGrids, which are two tools that
是新的统一2018.1的一部分 它将允许我们实际建模
are part of the new Unity 2018.1 which will allow us to actually model
每个屏幕截图的几何体
geometry per the screenshot.
这实际上是我创造的一个关卡 也就是在分区中
This is actually a level that I created and that is in the Distro.
它将允许我们在实际场景视图中创建几何图形
It will allow us to create geometry in the actual scene view
不需要进入像Blder或Maya这样的第三方程序
without needing to go into a third party program like Blender or Maya,
必须在这两者和进出口之间进行某种交替
and have to sort of alternate between the two and import and export
没完没了
incessantly.
不仅如此 而且一旦你建立了某种模型
Not only that, but as soon as you model something
像这样在场景视图中的Unity中 您
like this in Unity in the scene view, you
可以立即测试它的游戏性 并确保
can immediately test it for gameplay and make sure
它确实适合你想要的东西
that it actually fits what you want.
在导入时 您不必担心规模问题
And you don't have to worry about scale issues when you are importing
在某种程度上让它发挥作用 并最终弄清楚 “哦
and sort of making it work, and figuring out ultimately that, "Oh,
我不喜欢这个关卡的方式
I don't like the way this mesh this level is.
让我去调整一下 然后再重做一次
Let me go and tweak it and redo it."
它只会给你带来极大的轻松和灵活性
It just allows you a ton of ease and flexibility.
我之前提到过布拉克西斯
And I previously mentioned Braxis before,
但他有几个很棒的教程
but he's got a couple of awesome tutorials
在ProBuilder和ProGrids上补充以下内容
here on ProBuilder and ProGrids to supplement sort of what
我们将在课堂上讨论今天的内容
we'll talk about today in lecture.
但如果你想更多地展示这两种产品的所有功能
But if you want sort of more of a showcase of all the features of both,
然后你可以在这里观看这些视频 并对它们的工作原理有一个了解
then you can look at these videos here and get a sense of how they work.
因此 我们将继续讨论一下Pro Builder
So we're going to go ahead and just mess around with pro builder a little bit
在这里的场景视图中 我们可以看到它是什么样子的
here in the scene view so that we can see what it looks like.
我要打开我的另一个场景
I'm going to open up my other scene.
所以我有《门户》这一幕
So I have the "Portal" scene.
如果你在演播厅 这里是所有人
If you are in the Distro, this is where all the
我们一直在看的东西是存在的 只有“门户”游戏
stuff that we've been looking at exists, just the "Portal" game.
还有一个ProBuilder场景 我不打算保存它
There's a ProBuilder scene as well, which I'm going to not save that.
所以这个ProBuilder场景就是我之前创建的标高几何体
And so this ProBuilder scene is the level geometry that I created earlier.
现在看起来很可怕 因为我没有花太多时间
Now it looks pretty horrendous because I didn't spend a terrible amount of time
这就去
on it.
无论如何 我并不是一个特别有天赋的视觉设计师
And I'm not a particularly talented visual designer by any stretch.
让我继续把它弄大一点
Let me go ahead and make it a little bit larger
这样我们就能看得更清楚一点
so that we can see it a little better.
但它展示了一些有趣的功能
But it showcases some of the interesting features.
所以我们有明显的多边形正方形矩形几何图形
So we have obviously polygonal square shaped rectangular geometry.
我们可以看到 有些面有纹理 有些则没有
We can see that some faces are textured and some aren't.
例如 我们可以在这里看到这张脸
So we can see this face here, for example,
仅为白色材质 即默认材质
is just white material, the default material.
我们可以看到 所有这些都有砖块的纹理 这是我脱下的
We can see that all of these have this brick texture, which I got off
一个过程生成器网站 它允许
a procedural generator website that allows
您需要为您的纹理选择一个好的模板
you to choose a good template for your texture
然后指定颜色和类似的东西
and then specify colors and stuff like that.
我对这个纹理做了同样的事情
I did the same thing for this texture.
这是另一个程序纹理 它
This is another procedural texture, which
有点像蓝色的 马布利式的纹理
is kind of like a blue, marbley type texture.
最酷的是--至少在纹理方面
The cool thing about it is-- at least for texturing,
您可以只选择要设置纹理的任意面
you can just choose arbitrary faces that you want to texture,
而不是像你一样让整件事变得更有质感
rather than have to texture the whole thing like you
如果只为网格提供默认材质
would do if you were to just give a mesh a default material,
它将应用于整个网格
it'll apply to the whole mesh.
在本例中 它只是将其应用于我们在ProBuilder中选择的任何面
In this case, it's just applying it to whatever faces we select in ProBuilder.
另一件有趣的事 我真的很喜欢
Another interesting thing, which I really like,
ProBuilder为您提供了许多用于创建特殊类型几何的工具
is ProBuilder gives you a lot of tools for creating special kinds of geometry
非常快速和高效
very quickly and efficiently.
在这种情况下 这是一个楼梯 我所要做的就是
In this case, this is a staircase, which all I had to do
是与ProBuilder选择构建楼梯
was with ProBuilder select build staircase,
然后你可以选择很多不同的参数
and then you can choose a lot of different parameters.
我们稍后会看看如何做到这一点
We'll take a look at how to do that in a second.
我在这里也做了同样的事情
I did the same thing here.
所以请注意这个楼梯有一种螺旋形
So notice this staircase has kind of a spiral to it.
然后这个楼梯真的很高 但没有螺旋形
And then this staircase is really tall, but has no spiral.
然后我们这里有另一个楼梯 它
And then we have another staircase here, which
有点短 而且没有螺旋形
is kind of shorter and doesn't have a spiral,
然后它就到了这一点
and then it ends up coming up here to this point.
如果这就是任务 也许
And then if this were the assignment, maybe
这个地方就是你放置对撞机的地方
this spot here would be where you put your collider that
他说 “哦 这就是水平的结论
says, "OH, this the level's conclusion.
你已经达到了这个水平
You've been in the level."
所以任务是用ProBuilder制作一个关卡
So the assignment is with ProBuilder, make a level.
它不一定非得是什么非常奇特的东西
It doesn't have to be anything terribly fancy.
我不是一个伟大的设计师
I'm not a great designer.
但它至少应该有一个部分
But it should have at least one section where
你被要求跳跃 所以某种跳跃谜题
you're required to jump, so some sort of jump puzzle
只是为了让你能稍微考虑一下关卡的设计
just so that you can think about the design of your level a little bit.
它应该是有意义的大 它不一定是巨大的
And it should be meaningfully large, it doesn't have to be gargantuan.
它不应该很小 不应该是10米或--
And it shouldn't be small, it shouldn't be 10 meters or--
也许不是10米 但它不应该像5米那么大
maybe not 10 meters, but it shouldn't be like five meters large.
显然 这是非常小的
Obviously, that's very small.
这应该是你会考虑的一个相当大的水平
It should be something that you would consider a somewhat sizable level.
使用这种大小的东西是一个公平的衡量标准
Using something of this size is a fair metric.
所以ProBuilder--所以默认情况下 ProBuilder
So ProBuilder-- so by default, ProBuilder
未安装在您的项目中
is not installed in your project.
你必须去资产商店
You have to go to the Asset Store.
我不知道 Asset Store最近几天有点慢
I don't know, Asset Store has been a little bit slow last couple of days.
让我们看看它是不是很快就能奏效
Let's see if it works quickly.
看起来是这样的
It looks like it is.
因此 如果我们去资产商店打开--它又开始连接了
So if we go to the Asset Store and open-- it's connecting again,
它太慢了
it's being slow.
因此 如果您搜索资产 只需输入ProBuilder 它将在此处弹出
So if you search for assets and just type ProBuilder, it will pop up here.
请注意 上面写着联合技术
And notice that it says Unity technologies.
任何基本上写着联合技术的东西
Anything basically that says Unity technologies
将是Unity的一种免费补充
will be a free sort of supplement to Unity
您只需从Asset Store导入即可
that you can easily just import from the Asset Store.
现在这里的窗户有点挤 因为我用的是720p显示器
Now it's a little bit cramped the window here, because I'm in a 720p monitor.
但您只需点击下载 然后按顺序导入
But you just have to click Download, and then Import in order
将其导入到您的项目中
to import it into your project.
作业10的“门户”的配乐
The Distro for "Portal" for assignment 10
已安装ProBuilder和ProGrids
already has ProBuilder and ProGrids installed.
ProGrids将是完全相同的过程 只是ProGrids就在这里
ProGrids would be the exact same process, just ProGrids right here.
当您将这两项都导入到项目中时
And when you import both of those into your project,
您将立即拥有使用工具的能力
you'll immediately have the ability to go up to Tools.
你会在这里看到ProBuilder和ProGrid
And you'll see ProBuilder and ProGrids here.
您所需要做的就是点击ProBuilder 然后点击ProBuilder窗口
And all you need to do is click on the ProBuilder and then ProBuilder window.
你可以看到这个漂亮的小窗口弹出
And you can see here this nice little widget filled window pops up,
如果你想的话也可以把它停在这里
and you can also dock it here if you want to.
实际上 我是不小心的
Actually, I did that on accident.
但是Unity让它变得非常好
But Unity makes it pretty nice so you can dock
你想把东西放哪就放哪
your stuff wherever you want it to.
还有一些不同的东西
And there's a few different things.
所以你可以做一个新的形状和一个新的多边形
So you can do new shape and a new poly-shape.
新的形状实际上为您提供了形状模板
The new shape actually gives you shape templates.
在这里 我默认选择了立方体
So here, I have chosen just cube by default,
它可以让你做楼梯 棱柱 圆柱
and it allows you to do stairs, prisms, cylinder.
比如我可以做一个楼梯 然后
So I can just do a stair, for example, and then
我们马上就能看到这个楼梯网格
we immediately see this stair mesh here.
我可以通过改变滑块来生成我想要的步数
I can generate the number of steps that I want just by changing the slider.
如果我想的话 我可以改变它的曲率 这样它就成了一个旋转的楼梯
I can change the curvature if I want, so that it's a rotating staircase.
然后我还可以改变楼梯的宽度和高度
And then I can also change how wide and how tall the stairs are,
这个内半径就像台阶的深度
and also this inner radius is like how deep the steps are,
如果这说得通的话
if that makes sense.
所有这些加在一起 一旦你完成了
And then all of these together, once you've finished,
你只要点击build stair就可以了
you just hit build stair, and it's done.
现在你有了一个楼梯网格 你可以把它放在你关卡的任何地方
Now you have a stair mesh that you can just put anywhere in your level,
爬楼梯也很容易
and it's that easy to make stairs.
在我深入了解ProBuilder的工作原理之前
Before I get into more of what makes ProBuilder, work,
我将继续并启用ProGrid
I'm going to go ahead and enable ProGrids.
所以ProGrids是一个很酷的功能
So ProGrids is a cool feature.
这是一个很酷的附加功能 它实际上会锁定场景中的所有内容
It's a cool add on, which will actually lock everything in your scene
到一个特定的网格 您可以根据网格的精细或粗糙程度
to a specific grid which you can designate based on how fine or coarse
你想要的网格
you want the grid to be.
这将允许我们做的是 当我移动时
And what that will allow us to do is when I move,
注意它在网格上移动
notice that it's moving on the grid.
它不是连续运动的 它实际上是离散的步骤
It's not moving in a continuous motion, it's actually discrete steps.
这样做的好处是
And the advantage of doing things this way
当你在模拟你的水平或诸如此类的东西时
is that when you're modeling your level or whatnot--
假设你有一个你已经创建的图表或绘图
let's say you have maybe a diagram or a drawing that you've created.
你把它贴在一个纹理上 场景中的一个平面网格上
You slap it on a texture, a flat mesh in your scene,
然后你只需在上面画上你的标高
and then you just sort of draw your level on top of it,
当你创建你所有的几何体时 所有的东西都会被很好地、干净地映射出来
everything will map up nice and cleanly when you're creating all your geometry.
你可以把东西放在一起 它会把所有的东西都对齐在同一个轴上
And you can snap things together and it will align all on the same axis.
这使得创建这样的关卡变得容易得多
And it makes creating levels like this just a lot easier.
你不必担心事情会稍微有点不对劲
You don't have to worry about things being slightly off
然后像缺少顶点之类的东西
and then like missing vertices and everything
看起来有点不干净
be looking a little bit unclean.
这确保了一切都非常干净
This ensures that everything is very clean.
所以 再说一次 只要注意它在移动的离散的步骤
So again, just notice the discrete steps that it's moving.
这些都被锁定在这里的网格上
These are all locked to the grid here.
因此 您可以更改此处的所有设置 以确定其大小
And so you can change all the settings here as to how large it is.
如果我创建一个立方体
If I create a cube.
因此 我将继续创建一个新的立方体并构建它
So I'm going to go ahead and create a new cube and build it.
请注意 在这里 这四个按钮类似于
Notice up here these four buttons are like the modes with which
我们可以与我们的立方体互动
we can interact with our cube.
这与你在3D软件中得到的非常相似 比如Blder
And this is very similar to what you get in 3D software, like Blender,
玛雅 什么的
Maya, whatnot.
使用鼠标左键选择顶点 然后
You choose vertices with the left mouse, and then you
可以按Shift键选择多个 然后只需移动它即可
can hit shift to select multiple, and then you can just move it.
由于我使用的是ProGrids 它会将其捕捉到网格上 对吗？
And since I'm using ProGrids, it's snapping it to the grid, right?
因此 如果我关闭ProGrids 它应该是像这样连续的
So if I turn off ProGrids, it should just be continuous like that.
所以 你可以得到任何角度
And so, you can get whatever sort of angles
您的需求取决于您的用例
you want depending on what your use case is.
所以我要继续按下命令Z
So I'm going to go ahead and hit Command Z.
如果我点击脸部模式 然后点击这个脸部 然后按下Shift键
If I click on the face mode and I click this face and I shift click,
它实际上会挤压它 让它变成一个新的面孔
it'll actually extrude it and make a new face.
我可以一遍又一遍地做这件事
And I can keep doing this over and over again.
让我放大一点 这样我就能看得更清楚一点
Let me zoom out a little bit so I can see a little bit better.
然后我挤出那个 然后我挤出那个
And I extrude that, and then I extrude that.
对吗？
Right?
开始建造一些东西
Starting to build something.
它不是很漂亮 但它是一种东西
It's not beautiful, but it's something.
我可以再挤出一次
I can extrude that again.
我相信我也能扩大规模
I believe I can scale as well.
所以你可以像这样把它建起来
So you can build it out like that.
我也没有花太多时间去掌握
And I haven't spent a ton of time mastering
如何使用这个工具 以及它的所有细节 但它非常
how to use that tool and all the ins and outs of it, but it is very,
我认为 如果你想进入关卡设计 这很有用
I think, useful if you're looking to get into level design
并且您希望避免与第三方打交道的开销
and you want to avoid the overhead of dealing with third party
像Blender或Maya这样的软件 并拥有您正在
software like Blender or Maya and having model files that you're
导入和导出
importing and exporting.
这可能是一种痛苦
It can be kind of a pain.
然而 如果您想要导出模型 您绝对可以做到这一点
However, if you want to export models, you can definitely do that.
这里有一个方法--
There is a method here--
我都忘了是哪一个了
I forget which one it is off hand.
我想就是这个了
I think it's this one.
不是的
No.
其中之一允许您保存模型
One of these allows you to save the model.
我记不清具体是哪一个了
I don't remember exactly which one it is.
是这个吗？
Is it this one?
菜单有点挤 所以我要把它炸掉
The menu is a little bit cramped here, so I'm going to actually blow it up.
现在 我想不起来哪一个允许你真正的出口了
Offhand, I can't recall which of these allows you to actually export.
我还没有记住图标 因为它是一个相当新的工具
I don't have the icons memorized yet because it's a fairly new tool.
但其中之一将允许您实际出口
But one of these will allow you to actually export
对象为FBX或OBJ 无论您的软件是什么
the object as FBX or OBJ, whatever your software is
你最终会想要--
that you end up wanting to--
因此 您还可以转到此处的导出菜单 这是
so you can just also go up to here to the export menu, which is
更容易看到每件事的名字
a lot easier to see everything by name.
您还可以选择您想要的导出方式
And you can choose how you want it to export.
您也可以为您的游戏导出资产
You can also export assets too for your game
因此 您可以在场景中包含ProBuilder
so you can have objects in your scene that ProBuilder
将生成以供使用 因此您可以通过这种方式创建预制件
will generate for using, so you can create prefabs that way.
但这是OBJ 这样你就可以输出它了
But then here's OBJ so that you can export it
添加到您选择的3D软件
to your 3D software of choice.
这与以下情况有关 例如 您
This is relevant for situations where, for example, you
我想喜欢装备和模型 并为网格制作动画
want to like rig and model and animate a mesh.
你不能在ProBuilder中做任何形式的索具
You can't do any sort of rigging in ProBuilder,
但你可以在其他3D软件中做到这一点
but you can do that in other 3D software.
因此 以这种方式出口是有意义的
So it makes sense to export it that way.
您还可以在此处创建模型、将其导出、装配 然后重新导入
You can also create the model here, export it, rig it, and then re-import
如果你想的话 这是相关的
it if you want to, and that's relevant.
这是一个可用的场景 就像现在一样
This is a usable scene as is right now.
闪电变得有点混乱
The lightning gets a little bit messed up.
当你弄乱东西的时候 注意这里 但它会被修复
Notice here when you mess with stuff, but that gets fixed.
这里有一米 它在那里做一些计算
There's of meter here where it does some calculating.
默认情况下 它实际上会在所有对象上烘焙照明
And by default, it will actually bake lighting on all of your objects.
但现在 这将与你拥有的任何角色完美地碰撞
But as is, this will perfectly collide with any characters that you have.
所以我有一个FPS角色
So I have a FPS character.
我要把这家伙带上来 我们开始吧
I'm going to bring this guy up, let's go ahead
把变形放在这里 把他放在正确的位置
and set the transform up here, put him in the right position.
ProGrids正在连接它 使我所在的位置旁边的网格可见
And ProGrids is attaching that, making that grid visible next to where I am.
你可以为它设置轴
And you can set the axis for that.
目前 我实际上已将其禁用
Currently, I have it actually disabled.
因此 如果我现在启用它 这实际上会以增量的方式移动 看到了吗？
So if I enable it now, this will actually move in increments, see?
它会把它完美地捕捉到网格上
And it'll snap it to the grid perfectly.
但当我按下Play时 我应该就在这里的这个网子上
But as I hit play, I should just be on this mesh up here.
嗯
Yeah.
所以这只是场景的一部分 就像
And so this is just part of the scene now, like
就好像你是在搅拌机或玛雅或其他什么地方做的一样
as if you had made it in Blender or Maya or whatever.
如果你跳到我的实际水平 然后稍微探索一下
If you jump down to my actual level and then explore it a little bit,
这一切都是随意创造的
this is all just haphazardly created.
楼梯和其他网格之类的东西
Stairs and other meshes and stuff.
所以 要一路走到顶端
And so, make it all the way to the top.
我摔倒了
I fell down.
我也不擅长玩游戏
I'm also horrible at playing games.
但它的美妙之处在于你可以立即播放它 对吗？
But the beauty of it is you can just play it instantly, right?
就在大门外面
Right out the gate.
现在我想展示的另一件很酷的事情
Now another cool thing that I like to showcase
我们之前谈过灰色拳击
is we talked about gray boxing earlier.
对于制作内部级别 灰色拳击是
For making interior levels, gray boxing is
设置关卡并测试其可玩性的目的
the purpose of making levels and testing them for playability.
ProBuilder最酷的一点是它
The cool thing about ProBuilder is that it
有一个反法线功能 我认为这是
has a invert normals feature, which I think is just
通常可在3D软件中访问
generally accessible in 3D software.
我现在还不知道它在哪个菜单上
I don't know offhand which menu it's in.
动作、几何体、我是否选择了正确的内容？
Actions, geometry, do I have the right things selected?
好的 我要打开ProBuilder窗口
All right, I'm going to open up ProBuilder window.
其中之一就是反转选择
And then one of these is invert selection.
抱歉 等等
Sorry, wait.
翻转法线 开始吧
Flip normals, there we go.
所以 现在这是一个内部层面
And so, what this does is now this is an interior level.
所以我们之前所做的就是创建一个任意大小的多边形
So all we did before was we made a polygonal creation of arbitrary size
和造型
and shape.
如果你反转法线--回想一下每个3D多边形
If you invert the normal-- so recall every 3D polygon,
作为法线和任意方向的3D曲面
3D surface as a normal and whatever direction
这就是面对 朝着相反的方向 朝着正常的方向
that's facing, going the opposite way, going towards that normal
是所呈现的内容
is what gets rendered.
但在它的后面 如果你朝与地面相反的方向走
But behind it, if you're going in the opposite direction of the surface
正常情况下 它是隐形的
normal, it's invisible.
这样做的效果是 如果我们翻转一些东西的所有法线
And so, the effect of that is if we flip all the normals of something that
是凸的 我们就得到了一个室内场景
is convex, we get an interior scene.
如果我们从外面看
And if we're looking at it from the outside,
看起来有点奇怪 对吧？
it looks a little bit weird, right?
就像我们能看到它一样
Like we can see into it.
这就是你可能会在《我的世界》中看到的东西 例如
And this is something that you might see like in "Minecraft," for example,
当你在观察几何体的一部分时
when you're looking in part of the geometry
你应该看不到的东西
that you shouldn't be able to see.
你可以点击这个世界 看到所有其他的东西
You can click through the world and see all the other
就像世界的内陆地区 因为你基本上
like interior parts of the world because you've basically
超出了该多边形的表面法线
gone beyond the surface normal of that polygon,
你只能从这个角度来看问题
and you're only seeing the from that perspective
朝向您的方向的所有多边形的曲面法线
all the surface normals of polygons that are facing in your direction in that
道路
way.
但通常情况下 它会让你直视一切
But often, it will allow you to look straight through all
其他类型的立方体
of the other sort of cubes that are along the way
因为你看到的是它们表面法线的所有倒数
because you're looking at all the inverse of their surface normal,
你在朝那个方向看
you're looking in that direction.
因此 同样 多边形一次只能照亮一个方向
And so, again, only one direction can a polygon be lit at once.
即使我们从上面看 你也能看到这一点
And even if we look at it from the top, you can see that as well.
我们从上往下看 翻转法线
We're looking at it from the top, flip the normals,
它将成为一个凸起的3D对象
it becomes a convex 3D object.
把它们翻过来 现在是内层 对吧？
Flip them, now it's an interior level, right?
所以我真的要深入到这一点
So I'm actually going to go into this.
我将再次翻转法线
And I'm going to flip the normals again.
我要点击这个
I'm going to click on this.
事实上 我必须点击很多这样的东西 因为它分裂了网格
I have to click on a lot of these, actually, because it split up the mesh.
但这将是足够容易的
But it's going to be easy enough.
我正在点击所有的顶级服务
I'm clicking all the top services of this,
以确保我不会意外地在另一边弄到任何东西
making sure I didn't get any on the other side on accident.
我没有
I did not.
我要挤压这个 然后我要翻转所有的法线
I'm going to extrude this, and then I'm going to flip all the normals,
然后我要拿起我的FPS控制器 它在这里
and then I'm going to take my FPS controller, which is here,
事实上 我认为它已经在里面了 它确实在里面
and actually I think it's already inside, which it is.
我要按下播放键了
I'm going to hit play.
灯光 我不确定会不会搞砸
The lighting, I'm not sure if it will be messed up.
它搞砸了 因为它正在计算一堆东西
It is messed up because it is in the middle of calculating a bunch of stuff,
但现在 我用以前奇怪的网格创建了一个内层
but now I've created an interior level with the weird mesh that I had before.
所以 如果你把你的楼层做成这个凹形的东西
And so, if you make the building of your level this concave thing
然后你翻转所有的法线 你就可以创建一个室内场景
and then you flip all the normals, you can create an interior scene
很容易与天花板和其他一切
very easily with ceiling and everything else.
通常情况下 否则 这将是一种痛苦的屁股
Normally otherwise, it'd be kind of a pain in the butt.
但它使使用ProBuilder变得超级容易
But it makes it super easy to do with ProBuilder.
还有很多其他功能 材质编辑就是其中之一
And there's a lot of other features, a material editor for one.
因此 使用材质编辑器 您实际上可以指定特定的材质
So with the material editor, you can actually designate specific materials.
在本例中 我创建了几个材质
In this case, I've created a couple of materials.
这里是砖块纹理 还有大理石纹理 我用了一些纹理
A brick texture here, and a marble texture, which I took some textures,
创造了材料 使这些材料的反照率成分
created material, made the albedo component of those materials
那种质感
that texture.
这让我可以任意选择一张脸
And what that allows me to do is I can select an arbitrary face.
所以在这种情况下 我会选择这些面孔
So in this case, I'm going to choose these faces.
我只需点击这块砖的纹理
And I can just click on this brick texture.
现在 这些都是像那块砖一样的纹理
And now, these are textured as that brick.
它不是将其应用于整个网格 而是
It's not applying it to the entire mesh, it's
只是把它用在我们想要的任何特定的面孔上
just applying it to whatever specific face that we want to.
还有一个UV编辑器 它可以让你真正
And there's a UV editor, which will allow to actually take
模型的网格
the mesh of your model.
在这种情况下 这是我们的整个网状结构
In this case, this is our entire mesh here.
记住 就像我们上周讨论的那样
Just remember, as we talked about it last week,
所有的东西都被剪下来 弄平了
everything gets cut out and made flat.
所以你可以看到--
So you can sort of see--
如果你还记得我们正在处理的东西的形状
if you remember the shape of what we're dealing with,
所有由奇怪的大物体组成的多边形
all the polygons that comprised weird, large object.
它们现在都为我们展开了 所以我们可以非常容易地获取纹理
They're all now splayed out for us, so we can just very easily take a texture
把它放在我们想放的任何地方
and put it wherever we want on here.
现在我没有太多使用这个的经验
Now I don't have a ton of experience using this,
所以我不是百分之百地相信我有能力对眼前的东西进行紫外线贴图
so I'm not 100% confident in my ability to UV map something right now in front
怕你
of you.
但ProBuilder网站上的文档
But the documentation on the ProBuilder web site
详细介绍了如何使用它
goes in the detail as to how to use this.
因此 如果你想让特定的纹理出现在网格的一部分
So if you wanted say a specific texture to be in part of the mesh,
然后也许另一种纹理成为它的另一部分
and then maybe another texture to be another part of it
以一种特定的焊接方式 不会溅到上面
in a specific welded way that's not splat onto it,
UV编辑器将帮助您实现这一点
the UV editor would help you with that.
例如 角色模型上的一张脸或其他东西
For example, a face on a character model or something else.
或者像某个门上的牌子 或者类似的东西
Or maybe like a sign on a door somewhere, or something like that.
您可以在这里完成所有操作 只需单击并拖动所有的面
You can do that all here, just click and drag all the faces.
这些面实际上是相互依赖地进入的
The faces are actually entered dependent from one another
以便您可以将它们以适合您的纹理的方式进行布局
so that you can lay them out in a way that fits the texture that you
正试图将一切都映射到
are trying to map everything to.
简而言之 这就是ProBuilder
That is ProBuilder in a nutshell.
有很多功能
There's a lot of features.
我们没有时间涵盖所有这些问题
We don't have time to cover all of them.
我是说 坦率地说 我只是不知道
And I mean, frankly, I just don't know of all
其中一些非常好 只是因为这项技术是如此之新
of them super well yet just because the technology is so new.
但我认为这将是Unity未来的一大部分
But I think this is going to be a huge part of Unity's future
让人们可以访问它 否则可能会有
and making it accessible for people that would otherwise have maybe
因对其标高几何图形或其对象建模的想法而关闭
been turned off by the idea of modeling their level geometry or their object
几何图形
geometry.
我的意思是 当然对我来说 这让我想要在Unity中制作一款游戏
I mean, certainly for me, now this makes me want to make a game in Unity
现在 因为我知道我可以立即开始创造我的关卡
right now because I know I can instantly start creating my levels.
它很好 很容易 很方便
It's just nice and easy and convenient.
和ProGrids 您一定要同时使用ProGrids
And ProGrids, you should definitely use ProGrids in tandem
使用ProBuilder 这样您就可以以最佳方式重新安排事物
with ProBuilder so that you can optimally rearrange things in a way
所以它们都是均匀排列在一起的
so that they're all evenly lined up with each other.
否则 你最终会遇到一些问题
Otherwise, you're going to end up with issues
以一种非常具体的方式操纵他们的地位
in manipulating their position in a very specific way
然后来到这里 手动设置它们的值
and coming up here and setting their values manually.
这只是一种痛苦 所以容易得多
And that's just kind of a pain, so much easier
只是为了把所有的东西都放到网格上 ProGrids 并以这种方式处理它
just to snap everything to the grid, the ProGrids, and deal with it that way.
因此 这项任务在很大程度上正在进行
And so, the assignment is largely just going
要成为ProBuilder和ProGrids 只需与之平起平坐
to be take ProBuilder and ProGrids and just make a level with it.
然后利用我们学到的原则 创建一个控制器
And then just take the principles that we've learned, create a controller,
创建一个对撞机 只需创建一个非常简单的场景
create a collider, and just make a very simple scene.
否则 你可能会把时间花在你的期末项目上
And otherwise, probably spend your time focused on your final project.
那么 关于ProBuilder有什么问题吗？它是如何工作的 如何设置它？
So any questions as to ProBuilder, how it works, how to get it set up?
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：那么它看起来会是什么样子--一个角色真的能站在上面吗
AUDIENCE: So what would it look like-- can a character actually stand on top
拥有它的对象的[INAUDIBLE]
of an object that had it's [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：没有
COLTON OGDEN: No.
它应该会翻过它
It should flip through it.
让我继续把这个放在这里
Let me go ahead and put this up here.
事实上 我认为它仍然会引发碰撞
And actually I think it does still trigger collision,
但你将能够看穿--
but you'll be able to see through the--
观众：这只是视觉效果？
AUDIENCE: It's just visual?
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 这只是一种视觉效果
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah, it's just a visual.
这只是一个视觉上的错误 是一个闪电错误
It's just a visual bug, it's a lightning bug.
物理学应该仍然适用
The physics should still apply.
我要继续把模型放在这里
I'm going to go ahead and set the model up here.
好的
OK.
点击播放
Hit play.
不 实际上它看起来像是穿过了它
No, actually it looked like it went through it.
因此 它还反转了碰撞框
So it also inverts the collision box.
我看过一些游戏 在这些游戏中你可以穿透一些东西
I've seen some games where you can clip through something
并且仍然与之相撞
and still collide with it.
因此 我认为这最终取决于引擎或实现
So I think it depends on, ultimately, the engine or the implementation
你正在使用的东西
that you're using.
但在这种情况下 当你翻转这个网格的曲面法线时
But in this case, when you flip the surface normals here of this mesh,
它还会翻转网格碰撞器的法线
it also flips the mesh collider's normals.
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：最明显的做法就是复制它
AUDIENCE: The obvious thing to do would be copy it,
稍微估计一下 然后不要[INAUDIBLE]它
size it up a liitle bit, and then not [INAUDIBLE] it.
然后你会有一种内层和外层[INAUDIBLE].
And then you would have kind of an inner and outer layer [INAUDIBLE]..
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
COLTON OGDEN: Precisely, yeah.
如果你愿意 你可以复制一份内部装饰
If you wanted, you could make a copy of the interior.
我想你会把它改成同样大小的
You'd make it the same size, I suppose.
然后不要翻转 它是法线 所以你有一个壳和一个内部
And then not flip it's normals such that you have a shell and an interior.
是啊 当然了
Yeah, absolutely.
是啊 这要看情况
Yeah, it depends.
很多内部的层面 你永远不会超出他们的界限
A lot of interior levels, you will never ever be outside of their boundaries.
所以你不会经常看到这样的事情发生
And so you don't often see that happening,
但很大程度上 你可以让这种情况发生
but it's very much the case that you could have that happening.
例如 如果你有一个房屋模型 那么是的
And if you have like a house model, for example, then yeah.
你实际上会看到软管模型是用两个平面的墙来建模的
You'll actually see hosue models are modeled with walls that are two planes,
所以这里有一点厚度
so there's a bit of thickness.
它实际上是一个矩形 所以它可以
It's actually a rectangular shape, so it allows
你想要在一边和另一边发生碰撞
you to have a collision on one side and another side
因为对撞机有两个平面
because there's two planes of the collider,
而不仅仅是单个平面 后者是曲面法线的方向
rather than just the single plane, which is the direction of the surface normal.
关于ProBuilder还有其他问题吗？
Any further questions on ProBuilder?
嗯?
Yeah?
观众：那你怎么能从天花板上穿过去呢？
AUDIENCE: So how come you can [INAUDIBLE] through the ceiling
但不是从门进来的
but not through the door.
最上面有[INAUDIBLE]吗？
Is there [INAUDIBLE] in the top?
科尔顿·奥格登：因为底部的表面法线指向上方
COLTON OGDEN: Because the bottom's surface normal is pointed upward.
所以这里是朝上的
So this right here is pointed upwards.
但请注意 在这里 曲面法线实际上指向下方
But notice that here, the surface normal is actually pointed down.
因此您只能与曲面法线的方向碰撞
So you can only collide with the direction of the surface normal
这是你面临的问题 如果这有道理的话
that's facing you, if that makes sense.
你可以朝曲面法线的方向走
You can walk towards the direction of the surface normal,
但不是针对曲面法线 如果这是有意义的话
but not against the surface normal, if that makes sense.
这是Unity计算其网格渲染器组件的方式
That's the way that Unity calculates its mesh renderer component.
观众：嗯 也有左的和右的
AUDIENCE: Well, there's also left and the right.
所以左边是--你能从左边走到右边吗？
So the left is-- can you go through on the left to the right?
科尔顿·奥格登：你可以从这个方向穿过
COLTON OGDEN: You could go through from this direction,
但你不能走这个方向
but you could not go through this direction.
因为这个方向 曲面法线指向这个方向
Because this direction, the surface normal is pointed this way,
因此 如果我们试图与之背道而驰 我们就是在与正常情况相反
so if we try to walk against it, we'll be walking against the normal.
因此 我们将触发碰撞
And so, we will trigger a collision.
但如果你穿过它 你就会
But if you're walking through it in such that you're
沿着与曲面法线相同的方向
going the same direction as the surface normal,
所以如果你是从这个方向来的 那么它就不会检测到碰撞
so if you're coming from this direction then it won't detect a collision.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
嗯
Yeah.
Tany的建议是在它周围做一个贝壳
What Tany suggested, which was to make a shell around it,
就能解决这个问题
would solve that problem.
因此 如果我们创建这个精确的网格 复制它 然后反转它
So if we created this exact mesh, duplicated it, and then inverted it,
然后我们就会有两个相同的物体
then we would have two of the same object,
但是法线是单向的 法线是单向的
but with normals going one direction and normals going
另一个方向 以便网格渲染器
the other direction such that the mesh renderers
考虑到两个潜在的移动方向
account for both potential movement directions.
凉爽的
Cool.
好的
All right.
关于ProBuilder还有其他问题吗？
Any further questions on ProBuilder?
再说一次 这并不意味着是一个全面的教程
Again, not meant to be a comprehensive tutorial.
我在幻灯片中链接了一些视频和文档
There's videos and documentation that I've linked to in the slides,
但更多的是为了说明这个工具有多棒
but more just to illustrate how awesome this tool is really
这可能会挽救一些人做
and that this is probably going to save some people doing
如果您正在进行任何资产建模或关卡建模 则需要及时进行unity项目
Unity projects in time if you're doing any asset modeling or level modeling.
还有一件事--
Another thing that--
我没有为它做幻灯片 但我在课堂上谈到了
I didn't make a slide for it, but which I talked about in class
是着色器图形
was Shader Graph.
因此 着色器图形是另一个2018.1功能
And so, a Shader Graph is another 2018.1 feature,
这使得不必编写着色器
which allows rather than having to write shaders
在Shader Lab中 这是Unity的着色器语言 它可以相当
in Shader Lab, which is Unity's shader language, which can be quite
这是一次非常可怕的经历
an experience, quite intimidating.
你现在可以用这种基于节点的编程语言来创建它们--
You can actually create them now with this node based programming language--
不是真正的编程语言 而是这个节点基于
not really programming language, but this node based
我应该说是编程环境
programming environment, I should say.
这将允许您选择所有这些预设节点
Which will allow you to choose all these preset nodes that
影响着色器的行为
influence the shader's behavior.
而且有很多不同的种类
And there's a lot of different kinds.
这样做的结果是您可以看到着色器的每一步
And have the result of that be you can see your shader every step of the way,
所以着色器只是一系列的变换
so the shader is just a series of transformations going
在一个方向上从左到右
from left to right in one direction.
所有这些转变 你可以看到
All of these transformations, you can see
它们最终是如何累积起来产生这种最终效果的
how they end up accumulating to produce this final effect.
在这种情况下 这里--
In which case here--
如果这可能有点难的话 是一个海军陆战队的家伙带着这些蓝洞
if it maybe kind of hard to dicern, is a marine guy with these blue holes
实际上是在掩盖他的网状结构
that are actually masking his mesh.
我们早些时候谈到了遮盖
And we talked about masking earlier.
该着色器本身看起来像是应用了一个带有此噪波的遮罩
This shader itself looks like it's applying a mask with this noise that
正在产生
is generating.
它带有噪声产生功能 产生节点
And it comes with noise generation functions, generation nodes,
这将允许您将这些内容提供给着色器的质量组件
which will allow you to feed those into the mass component of your shader
然后产生一些非常有趣的酷炫效果
and then produce some very interesting cool effects.
否则 这将是一种--
Otherwise, this would be kind of--
除非你是着色器专家 而我不是 否则事情会很复杂
unless you're a shader expert, which I am not, it would be pretty complicated
仅仅用代码来实现这样的东西并不是一件容易的事情
and non-trivial to implement something like this with just code.
但这会为您生成代码 这样您就不会
But this generates code for you, such that you don't
必须实际编写任何代码
have to actually write any code at all.
但您仍然可以看到生成的着色器
But you can still see the produced shader that
从着色器图形为您创建
gets created for you from shader graph.
我相信它现在只是一种资产 我不能百分之百确定
I believe that it's just a asset now, I'm not 100% sure.
我没有测试过这个
I didn't test this going in.
希望我不只是怀念它
Hopefully, I'm not just missing it.
据推测 您应该能够直接导入它
Supposedly, you should be able to just import it.
我不是100%
I'm not 100%.
让我们看看你实际上是如何--它说这篇文章可能会使用它
Let's see how you actually-- it said this article maybe uses it.
通过Package Manger
Via the Package Manger.
我想这是一个新的窗口包管理器
I think this is a new Window Package Manager.
于是我们转到Window 然后转到Package Manager
So we to Window and then Package Manager.
然后就是一切
And then all.
然后是着色器图形
And then Shader Graph.
嗯
Yeah.
所以就在这里
So right here.
依次选择Window、Package Manager和Shader Graph
So Window, and then Package Manager, and then Shader Graph
这将允许你输入这些手段
and that will allow you to import the means
我用它来创建这些图表布局 如果您使用
by which I create these graph layouts if you're using
2018.1 这门课程正在使用它
2018.1, which the course is using.
但如果你在家使用2017.4 那么更新到2018.1
But if you're at home and you're using 2017.4, then update to 2018.1,
您应该在包管理器中看到这一点
and you should see this in your package manager.
一旦你做到了这一点 你实际上可以
And then once you do that, you can actually
创建新的Shader Graph对象
create a new Shader Graph object.
然后你会看到它是场景中弹出的一个新窗口
And then you'll see it as a new window that pops up in your scene,
然后您就可以开始添加节点了
and then you can start adding nodes.
我没有为它准备任何材料
I don't have any material prepared for it,
我也没有预料到一定要谈论这件事
and I didn't anticipate talking about it necessarily,
但这似乎是一件非常改变游戏规则的事情
but it's something that seems to be very game changing.
这是虚幻已经存在很长时间的东西
And it's something that Unreal has had for a long time that
在我看来 它在某种程度上有别于统一
sort of differentiated it from Unity, in my opinion.
我认为他们有一件非常有价值的事情
And I think a very valuable thing that they've
他补充说 这表明2018年取得了很多令人惊叹的进展
added that shows a lot of awesome progress for 2018.
所以 再说一次 如果你想知道详细信息 可以链接到Braxis
So, again, a link to Braxis if you want details
关于如何使用--不仅是ProBuilder ProGrid
on how to use-- not only ProBuilder ProGrid,
但也有很多其他很棒的Unity功能 做了很多很酷的事情
but a lot of other awesome features of Unity and to do a lot of cool stuff.
他制作了一些很酷的视频
He makes some really cool videos.
作业10 因此作业10将使用ProBuilder创建一个级别
Assignment 10, so assignment 10 is going to be creating a level with ProBuilder
只是为了把你的手弄湿
just to get your hands wet with it.
水平应该是相当复杂的
The level should be pretty complex.
所以就像我之前说的 不像是一个完成的游戏级别
So like I said earlier, not like a finished game level.
我不期望你做很棒、很棒、很不可思议的事情
I'm not expecting you to do awesome, amazing, incredible things.
但这一层可能有几个有趣的几何图形
But a level that has maybe a few pieces of interesting geometry,
可能会生成一些楼梯 有一些可以生成的管道
maybe generate some stairs, has some pipes you can generate,
还有其他一些事情
and some other things.
里面有一个跳跃拼图
Have a jumping puzzle in there.
所以这意味着玩家应该有一个跳跃谜题
So this says there should be one jumping puzzle for the player,
任务还没有正式说明
the assignment doesn't officially say it yet,
但我要做个改变 让它成为
but I'm going to make a change to make it say
应该有一个跳跃拼图
that there should be a jumping puzzle.
你可以随心所欲地解释这一点 只需几个平台就可以了
You can interpret this however you want, just a couple of platforms is fine.
但说实话 你想要什么都行
But honestly, whatever you would like.
并且有两种不同的质地或材质
And have two different textures or materials.
因此 您只需导入您想要的任何纹理
So you can just import whatever texture you want,
或者 您可以访问允许您创建纹理过程的网站
or you can go to a website that allows you to procedure the create a texture.
你可以把它分配给一种材料 把它
And you can assign it to a material, put it
在ProBuilder的材质编辑器中 然后使用
in the material editor of ProBuilder, and then use
也就是说 如果您愿意 可以将其指定给一个面或整个对象
that to assign it to a face or to the whole object, if you want to.
但至少应该有两个 而不是默认的
But there should be at least two, not the default,
所以为了让它变得有点有趣
so to make it a little interesting.
如果愿意 您可以使用更多 但只需要两个
You can use many more if you want to, but only two are required.
所以这应该是一种完整的场景
So this should be kind of like a complete scene.
因此 将新场景与ProBuilder场景分开
So make a new scene separate from the ProBuilder scene,
独立于“门户”场景 包括一个FPS控制器
separate from the "Portal" scene, include an FPS controller
这样我们就可以在创建网格后立即在场景中移动
so that we can move around the scene immediately after creating the mesh,
对吗？
right?
但话虽如此 您可以使用默认控制器
But that said, you can use the default controller.
你不需要做任何花哨的事情
You don't need to do anything fancy.
然后在最后 你应该在对撞机上有一个触发器
And then at the very end, you should have a trigger on a collider
在某个地方 它可能是看不见的
somewhere, which can be invisible.
它不一定是隐形的 你可以让它成为你想要的任何东西
It doesn't have to be invisible, you can make this whatever you want.
你可以做得像一个拱门 或者--
You can make like an arch or--
我不知道
I don't know.
你可以尽情发挥你的想象力
You're free to use your imagination as much as you want,
但需要有一些对撞机 无论它是不是隐形的
but there needs to be some collider, whether it's invisible or not
在最后一刻
at the very end.
需要有一个触发器 然后当你与它相撞时
And there needs to be a trigger, and then when you collide with it,
屏幕上应该写着“关卡完成”
it should say, "Level Complete" on the screen.
所以只需从Unity2D中获取一个文本对象 这是画布的一部分
So just take a text object from Unity 2D, part of the canvas.
如果您只是在场景中添加一个UI文本 它
If you just add a UI text in the scene, it
将自动为您添加画布和活动系统
will automatically add a canvas and an event system for you.
创建标签 然后将其设置为开或关
Create the label, and then just set it on or off,
这取决于你是否撞上了扳机
depending on whether or not you've collided with the trigger.
在直升机游戏的“游戏结束”文本脚本中有这方面的代码
There is code for this in the helicopter game in the "Game Over" text script.
您可以确切地看到这是如何完成的
You can see exactly how this is done.
它有效地将文本的颜色设置为0000对0001
All it effectively is setting the color of the text to 0000 vs 0001,
或者任何你想要的有效的颜色 只是为了改变Alpha
or whatever color you want to effectively just to change on the alpha
文本颜色的组件
component of the text color.
一旦完成 你就有了一个完整的任务
And then once that's done, then you have a complete assignment.
然后你就可以花更多的精力
And then you can spend more energy.
希望 这应该只需要一个小时 也许更短
Hopefully, this should only take maybe an hour, maybe less.
你可以把更多的精力花在你的期末项目上 该项目将于11日到期
You can spend more energy on your final project, which will be due on the 11th.
但总的来说 教授这门课程是一种令人敬畏的乐趣
But altogether, it's been an awesome pleasure teaching this course.
我希望你们中的许多人能够学到很多有趣的东西
And I hope that a lot of you were able to learn a lot of interesting things
希望受到启发去创造一些你自己的项目
and hopefully were inspired to create some of your own projects
并将在未来继续创造一些你自己的产品
and will continue to create some of your own products in the future.
我当然喜欢做很多东西 特别是《超级马里奥》
I certainly enjoyed making a lot of the stuff, especially "Super Mario
兄弟们 “
Brothers."
我想那是我最喜欢的
I think that was my favorite.
但这是GD50
But this was GD50.
所以非常感谢你们
So thank you so much.